<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
    <atom:link href="https://technode.global/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
    <description>Latest news and trends about tech</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:43:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-technode-icon-2020_512x512-32x32.png</url>
      <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore’s UltraGreen.ai delivers 24 percent revenue growth in FY2025 to $142.4M</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/singapores-ultragreen-ai-delivers-24-percent-revenue-growth-in-fy2025-to-142-4m/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[UltraGreen.ai]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117493</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />UltraGreen.ai Limited, the Singapore-based fluorescence-guided surgery and digital health solutions provider backed by Temasek entity 65 Equity Partners, has delivered 24 percent revenue growth in the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025) to $142.4 million.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://ultragreen.ai/">UltraGreen.ai Limited</a>, the Singapore-based fluorescence-guided surgery and digital health solutions provider backed by Temasek entity 65 Equity Partners, has delivered 24 percent revenue growth in the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025) to $142.4 million.</p>
<p>The firm said in a statement on Wednesday that the results were driven by continued global adoption of Indocyanine Green (ICG) use in fluorescence-guided surgeries, across a growing range of procedures and specialties, alongside disciplined commercial execution as well as geographical expansion.</p>
<p>Its revenue growth was underpinned by both volume growth and improved pricing internationally. </p>
<p>Its sales volumes increased 13% year-on-year, while average selling prices rose across key markets, particularly in the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s gross margin maintained at 85 percent even as volumes continued to scale. </p>
<p>Its operating profit increased to $84.2 million, despite higher operating expenses associated with planned investments in commercial scale-up particularly in Asia, regulatory<br />
capabilities and initial public offering (IPO)-related costs.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s reported net profit after tax (NPAT) included net exceptional items of approximately $11.8 million. </p>
<p>Thiswas primarily related to a gain on the sale of discontinued non-core UltraLinQ business operations of approximately $23.7 million in August 2025, partially offset by a tax provision on dividend income of approximately $8.5 million and impairment and other charges totaling approximately US$3.4 million, including impairments related to assets held for sale and loss on disposal of intangible assets.</p>
<p>Excluding these exceptional items, the firm&#8217;s underlying NPAT increased 14 percent year-on-year to $63.8 million compared to $56 million.</p>
<p>The group ended FY2025 with no debt and a strong net cash position of $176.1 million, providing financial flexibility to support future growth initiatives.</p>
<p>“FY2025 marked a significant milestone for UltraGreen, culminating in our successful IPO in Singapore in December, with most of the offer being taken up by institutional investors, </p>
<p>&#8220;Even as we executed the listing process, we continued to deliver strong operating and financial performance and focus of our business model,&#8221; said Ravinder Sajwan, Chief Executive Officer and Executive Director of UltraGreen.ai.</p>
<p>&#8220;Looking ahead, we expect to continue delivering strong operational and financial growth, with FY2026 revenue forecast of between $170 million to $190 million,</p>
<p>&#8220;This outlook is driven by underlying business expansion, the full-year impact of pricing initiatives implemented in FY2025, and further penetration into new markets,&#8221; he added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="drslwOi2u9"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/12/03/ultragreen-ai-receives-strong-demand-for-400m-sgx-ipo/">UltraGreen.ai receives strong demand for $400M SGX IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;UltraGreen.ai receives strong demand for $400M SGX IPO&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/12/03/ultragreen-ai-receives-strong-demand-for-400m-sgx-ipo/embed/#?secret=C8OQa6nrfx#?secret=drslwOi2u9" data-secret="drslwOi2u9" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s AirAsia MOVE revenue exceeds $165M in 2025</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/malaysias-airasia-move-revenue-exceeds-165m-in-2025/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Transformation]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[airasia MOVE]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117491</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />AirAsia MOVE, the digital arm of Malaysia-based Capital A, saw its revenue exceeded MYR 641 million ($165 million) in 2025. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/Screenshot-2024-07-26-133957-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.airasia.com/en/gb">AirAsia MOVE</a>, the digital arm of Malaysia-based Capital A, saw its revenue exceeded MYR 641 million ($165 million) in 2025. </p>
<p>The firm said in a statement on Wednesday that its earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) for the year stood at MYR 84 million ($21.62 million) and MYR 65 million ($16.73 million) in net operating profit (NOP), resulting in profit after tax (PAT) of over MYR 54 million ($13.9 million) and reinforcing its return to sustained profitability.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, driven by the launch of the business to business (B2B) business — which contributed approximately 55 percent of revenue —as well as continued personalization initiatives, revenue in the fourth quarter of 2025 tripled quarter on quarter and nearly doubled year on year to MYR 300 million ($77.21 million). </p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s margins remained resilient, supported by minimal marketing spend under AirAsia MOVE’s unique social-led acquisition model, delivering an EBITDA of MYR 45 million ($11.58 million) and NOP of MYR 40 million ($10.29 million). </p>
<p>Its NOP margin also saw a significant 6 percentage points quarter on quarter uptick due to lower interest expense. </p>
<p>Excluding B2B, the firm&#8217;s flights transactions climbed 12 percent quarter on quarter, while gross booking value (GBV) rose 28 percent quarter on quarter on higher average spend. </p>
<p>Its performance was underpinned by a market-leading ancillary strategy with attach rates 23 percent higher than peer online travel agents (OTAs).</p>
<p>It is noted that its flights also secured two major partnerships with VietJet and IndiGo to further diversify its portfolio. </p>
<p>Stays continued to gain traction, with conversion improving to 2.3 percent from 1.9 percent a year ago, pushing the firm&#8217;s transactions up 2 percent and growing GBV 18 percent year on year. </p>
<p>Duty Free also outperformed, with GBV increasing 157 percent year on year, following the commencement of operations in the Philippines and Indonesia.</p>
<p>“This year, we will double down on content to drive user acquisition and conversion, </p>
<p>&#8220;By leveraging user-generated content and deeper community engagement, we aim to attract higher-intent users while optimizing marketing spend,&#8221; said AirAsia MOVE Chief Executive Officer Nadia Zahir Omer.</p>
<p>According to him, this will be enabled by continued investment in technology, including the development of the firm&#8217;s virtual concierge, to enhance the booking experience, thereby improving retention and lifting NPS. </p>
<p>&#8220;At the same time, we will pursue greater Stays growth by leveraging our flight-anchored flywheel, deepening hotel partnerships and launching more personalized bundles to increase attach rates and customer lifetime value,&#8221; she added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="GfHMGZz25f"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/12/02/airasia-moves-revenue-eases-to-27-13m-in-third-quarter-on-softer-flight-volumes/">AirAsia MOVE&#8217;s revenue eases to $27.13M in third quarter on softer flight volumes</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;AirAsia MOVE&#8217;s revenue eases to $27.13M in third quarter on softer flight volumes&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/12/02/airasia-moves-revenue-eases-to-27-13m-in-third-quarter-on-softer-flight-volumes/embed/#?secret=mEMd3PWIHk#?secret=GfHMGZz25f" data-secret="GfHMGZz25f" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StateSquare Capital to acquire controlling stake in Singapore’s Advanced Integrated Manufacturing</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/statesquare-capital-to-acquire-controlling-stake-in-singapores-advanced-integrated-manufacturing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Deep Tech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Advanced Integrated Manufacturing]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117488</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Singapore's private equity firm StateSquare Capital is acquiring a controlling stake in Advanced Integrated Manufacturing Corp. Pte Ltd (AIM), a Singapore-based aerospace and defense electronics manufacturing services (EMS) platform.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-145658-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>Singapore&#8217;s private equity firm StateSquare Capital is acquiring a controlling stake in <a href="http://www.aimcorp.com.sg/">Advanced Integrated Manufacturing Corp. Pte Ltd (AIM)</a>, a Singapore-based aerospace and defense electronics manufacturing services (EMS) platform.</p>
<p>StateSquare Capital said in a statement on Thursday that the firm will invest in AIM to drive its organic expansion and international acquisitive acceleration across Europe and North America, further strengthening AIM’s position as a leading independent EMS provider to global aerospace and defense customers.</p>
<p>Under StateSquare’s ownership, AIM will pursue a clearly defined value-creation strategy focused on organic capability and capacity expansion, alongside a targeted international buy-and-build program across Europe and North America. </p>
<p>AIM was founded in 1999 and serves global aerospace and defense customers from its operations in Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia, and the United Kingdom. </p>
<p>The Company provides a comprehensive suite of flight-critical, end-to-end electronic and mechanical manufacturing solutions, spanning prototyping, production, assembly, and testing.</p>
<p>The investment in AIM is underscored by its strong technical capabilities and robust quality systems, evidenced by long-standing Nadcap accreditation, as well as AS9100 and ISO9001 certifications – meeting the highest standards required by the global aerospace industry.</p>
<p>StateSquare’s investment DNA is rooted in global buy-and-build mid-market private equity partnerships and the firm has earmarked significant follow-on capital to support AIM’s transformational growth journey.</p>
<p>Closing of the investment is expected to occur by first quarter of 2026.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are excited to partner with AIM’s leadership to further scale the Company into a global aerospace and defense manufacturing solutions provider of choice for leading avionics original equipment manufacturers (OEMs), </p>
<p>&#8220;Our transformational value creation strategy for AIM is centered on a clearly defined global buy-and-build roadmap – an investment strategy deeply embedded in StateSquare’s leadership,&#8221; said Florian Marquis, Managing Partner and Chief Executive Officer of StateSquare Capital.</p>
<p>Joseph Khoo, Partner at StateSquare Capital, said they believe that the global aerospace and defense sector benefits from strong structural growth drivers. </p>
<p>&#8220;In addition, we are excited to onboard experienced EMS and aerospace industry veterans onto the company’s board to further drive the company’s long-term strategy and support the institutionalization of AIM in the years to come,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>Dr. Tan Kim Yong, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of AIM, said StateSquare Capital’s global investment approach, combined with its strong local expertise, makes them the perfect partner for them. </p>
<p>&#8220;While AIM was founded in Asia, we have been successfully serving global customers across Europe and North America for decades,</p>
<p>&#8220;StateSquare Capital’s early and clear commitment to further invest in the growth of AIM’s platform gave us the confidence to partner with Florian and his team,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>Nicholas Tan, Chief Operating Officer of AIM, said as the company reaches an inflection point in its accelerating global growth, and in alignment with their chairman’s intent to ensure long-term continuity and scalability of the business, they have chosen to partner with the StateSquare team as their preferred growth partner to work alongside management to significantly scale AIM and support their growth capital needs in the years to come. </p>
<p>&#8220;AIM is recognized for its strong, customer-centric operating ethos – a philosophy closely shared by the StateSquare team, </p>
<p>&#8220;By leveraging their global experience and ecosystem, we are excited to advance our shared vision and sustainable growth strategy for AIM, creating long-term value for our customers, stakeholders, and our dedicated employees,&#8221; he added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dTn6ewAoYh"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/">Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/embed/#?secret=iPg68Bq1lA#?secret=dTn6ewAoYh" data-secret="dTn6ewAoYh" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ant Digital Technologies strengthens AI infrastructure in Malaysia to boost local customer service capabilities</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/ant-digital-technologies-strengthens-ai-infrastructure-in-malaysia-to-boost-local-customer-service-capabilities/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 06:44:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117485</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />ZOLOZ, the flagship artificial intelligence (AI) product of Ant Digital Technologies, has announced the launch of its operations hub in Malaysia, which will upgrade its local service offerings, accelerate response times, and enhance on-the-ground processing capabilities to better serve Malaysian customers.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-144354-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>ZOLOZ, the flagship artificial intelligence (AI) product of<a href="https://intl.antdigital.com/en"> Ant Digital Technologies</a>, has announced the launch of its operations hub in Malaysia, which will upgrade its local service offerings, accelerate response times, and enhance on-the-ground processing capabilities to better serve Malaysian customers.</p>
<p>ZOLOZ said in a statement on Wednesday through its advanced technological framework—which incorporates artificial intelligence, facial recognition, and dynamic risk intelligence — the firm has successfully supported users across 30 countries and regions, delivering secure and seamless digital identity solutions.</p>
<p>“Building on our successful operations in Hong Kong SAR, Singapore, and Indonesia, the establishment of the ZOLOZ Malaysia hub represents another key milestone for Ant Digital Technologies in the International market,</p>
<p>“This demonstrates our commitment to invest in local digital infrastructure and deliver advanced AI solutions tailored to the specific needs of Malaysian customers,&#8221; said Garry Sien, Chief Innovation and Solutions Officer, International, Ant Digital Technologies. </p>
<p>Last Year, Malaysia has introduced the National Cloud Computing Policy (NCCP), setting out the country’s direction for cloud adoption and digital transformation, with an emphasis on security, inclusivity and sustainability. </p>
<p>According to the e-Conomy SEA 2025report released by Google, Temasek and Bain &amp; Company, Malaysia captured 32 percent of Southeast Asia’s total AI funding, positioning the country as a leading destination for AI investment in the region.</p>
<p>In April 2025，Ant Digital Technologies established its international headquarters in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>With the launch of its new regional hub, Ant Digital Technologies marks a new step in deepening its service capabilities and reaffirms its long-term commitment to the global market.</p>
<p>To date, Ant Digital Technologies has served over 10,000 enterprise clients and more than 300 ecosystem partners. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="iKd6nsUMKC"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/09/18/alipay-to-help-laver-cup-drive-fanbase-growth-and-digital-engagement-in-new-sponsorship/">Alipay+ to help Laver Cup drive fanbase growth and digital engagement in global sponsorship</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Alipay+ to help Laver Cup drive fanbase growth and digital engagement in global sponsorship&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/09/18/alipay-to-help-laver-cup-drive-fanbase-growth-and-digital-engagement-in-new-sponsorship/embed/#?secret=DkOUJo3VX8#?secret=iKd6nsUMKC" data-secret="iKd6nsUMKC" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Realty]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117405</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Digital Realty, the global cloud- and carrier-neutral data center platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Digital Realty Innovation Lab (DRIL) into Singapore, Japan and London. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.digitalrealty.com/">Digital Realty</a>, the global cloud- and carrier-neutral data center platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Digital Realty Innovation Lab (DRIL) into Singapore, Japan and London. </p>
<p>This marks the first expansion of the company’s global DRIL network into Asia Pacific and Europe, following the successful launch of the inaugural DRIL facility in Northern Virginia in September 2025, which has received acclaim from enterprise customers, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>The new DRIL locations will offer the firm&#8217;s ecosystem of partners and customers fully supported, real-world testing environments where they can bring their own workloads or use pre-configured infrastructure to validate AI and hybrid cloud deployments before scaling. </p>
<p>This is especially important as AI adoption increases and infrastructure readiness has emerged as a critical barrier to moving from experimentation to production at scale. </p>
<p>All three are expected to be available for use by customers and partners this year.</p>
<p>The launch represents Digital Realty’s commitment to support Singapore, Japan and the United Kingdom’s continued leadership in artificial intelligence (AI) innovation. </p>
<p>In Singapore, AI adoption is driving continued growth in the nation’s digital economy, which now accounts for 18.6 percent of total gross domestic product (GDP). </p>
<p>Japan also plans to invest 10 trillion yen ($64.12 billion) or more in the semiconductor and AI sectors by 2030. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the United Kingdom’s AI sector continues to accelerate, with more than 5,800 AI companies now operating nationwide, sector revenue reaching £23.9 billion ($32.42 billion) and AI generating £11.8 billion ($16 billion) in gross value added (GVA).</p>
<p>According to the statement, the Singapore DRIL is designed to serve as a digital innovation hub, bringing together local customers, partners, and research institutions with global technology providers and industry participants seeking to develop, test and deploy AI and hybrid cloud solutions in Singapore.</p>
<p>In Japan, the DRIL will be located at the company’s NRT12 data center in the Greater Tokyo area. </p>
<p>Designed to support advanced AI and high-performance computing use cases, it will feature 20 racks with direct liquid cooling (DLC) capabilities, enabling support for high-power-density workloads.</p>
<p>The DRIL in the UK will be in London, providing customers and partners with a dedicated environment to test and validate AI and hybrid cloud deployments before full-scale implementation.</p>
<p>“Sustaining rapidly expanding digital economies requires innovation ecosystems built on infrastructure that is not only AI-ready, but also efficient, resilient, and trusted,” said Serene Nah, Managing Director and Head of Asia Pacific, Digital Realty.</p>
<p>According to her, since launching the DRIL in the United States, they have seen strong demand from customers and partners across Asia Pacific seeking dedicated environments to validate AI and hybrid cloud architectures before deploying at scale. </p>
<p>&#8220;Bringing this capability to Singapore and Japan reflects the digital maturity of these markets and their critical role in shaping the region&#8217;s long-term digital competitiveness, </p>
<p>&#8220;By creating spaces where enterprises can test, optimize, and de-risk their AI infrastructure, we&#8217;re accelerating responsible deployment and strengthening Asia Pacific&#8217;s position as a hub for trusted digital innovation,&#8221; she added. </p>
<p>Séamus Dunne, Managing Director, UK &amp; Ireland, Digital Realty, said European AI adoption is expected to grow rapidly, and London sits at the center of that growth.</p>
<p>“Launching the Digital Realty Innovation Lab in London gives enterprises and partners a real-world environment to validate AI and hybrid cloud architectures before rolling them out across live environments, </p>
<p>&#8220;It’s a critical step in helping organizations deploy next-generation infrastructure faster, and with greater confidence,” he added. </p>
<p>The new DRIL locations will enable businesses throughout Asia Pacific and Europe to test performance, optimize configurations, and seamlessly connect to cloud and network providers via ServiceFabric, Digital Realty’s global interconnection and orchestration platform.</p>
<p>By leveraging Digital Realty’s global experience in deploying AI-ready infrastructure and its proven Pervasive Datacenter Architecture (PDx) methodology, the DRIL enables customers to test, optimize, and validate AI deployments in real-world conditions, reducing complexity and significantly accelerating the journey from pilot to production.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qXTWhYQycC"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/">IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/embed/#?secret=X1FGuVHHwu#?secret=qXTWhYQycC" data-secret="qXTWhYQycC" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zetrix AI]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117402</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />The World Bank Group, through its private sector arm the International Finance Corporation (IFC), has announced a $40 million equity investment in Zetrix AI Berhad, to improve access to Digital Public Infrastructure (DPI) services in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>The World Bank Group, through its private sector arm the International Finance Corporation (IFC), has announced a $40 million equity investment in <a href="https://www.zetrix.com/">Zetrix AI Berhad</a>, to improve access to Digital Public Infrastructure (DPI) services in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.</p>
<p>IFC said in a statement on Wednesday that the investment will support the development and rollout of new, blockchain-based DPI applications and artificial intelligence (AI)-enabled products that aim to improve digital inclusion, access to services, and economic efficiency in Malaysia and the broader ASEAN region. </p>
<p>In Malaysia, these new services would integrate with the country’s digital ecosystem through MyDigital ID, the country’s digital identity system, and the Malaysia Blockchain Infrastructure (MBI), the country’s national blockchain service network. </p>
<p>Zetrix AI’s DPI applications and products aim to make a range of services more efficient, secure, and cost-effective, including the verification of digital IDs through to the digitalization of international trade and the tokenization of real-world assets, among others. </p>
<p>The investment will also support Zetrix AI’s expansion of its DPI services into emerging markets in ASEAN and the rest of the world. </p>
<p>“This investment reflects IFC’s commitment to advancing Malaysia’s digital transformation agenda, in line with the Thirteenth Malaysia Plan, 2026-2030,</p>
<p>“The development of Digital Public Infrastructure services is essential to improving public service delivery, strengthening economic competitiveness, and ensuring that growth is inclusive and sustainable,&#8221; said Judith Green, World Bank Group Country Manager for Malaysia. </p>
<p>She also said the investments like this allow them to scale innovative digital solutions and support the creation of resilient, secure and interoperable systems that expand access to services and opportunities for both people and businesses in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, TS Wong, Group Managing Director of Zetrix AI, said from digital IDs to digitized customs clearance processing to large language models and stable coins, the real-world cross-border use cases in blockchain and AI that they are deploying are aimed at catalyzing disruptive transformation across ASEAN and enabling deeper socio-economic integration in the region.</p>
<p>“With the participation and market access from IFC, we will accelerate our global expansion plans,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>Headquartered in Malaysia, Zetrix AI, formerly known as MY E.G. Services Berhad, started operations in 2000 as a firm in the provision of electronic government services and complementary commercial offerings in Malaysia. </p>
<p>The firm is currently deploying blockchain technology and AI in supporting the public and private sectors across ASEAN.</p>
<p>It is leveraging its Layer-1 blockchain platform Zetrix and the convergence of Web3, AI and robotics to enable optimally-efficient, intelligent and secure cross-border transactions, digital identity interoperability and automation solutions that connect people, businesses and governments.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="P0aYj9fXCU"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/11/12/zetrix-ai-partners-fmff-to-boost-digitalization-of-cross-border-trade-through-ztrade/">Zetrix AI partners FMFF to boost digitalization of cross-border trade through ZTrade</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Zetrix AI partners FMFF to boost digitalization of cross-border trade through ZTrade&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/11/12/zetrix-ai-partners-fmff-to-boost-digitalization-of-cross-border-trade-through-ztrade/embed/#?secret=sPearsrjGo#?secret=P0aYj9fXCU" data-secret="P0aYj9fXCU" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mambu expands payments hub into Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/mambu-expands-payments-hub-into-indonesia-the-philippines-malaysia-and-singapore/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117397</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-102325-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" />Mambu, a global software as a service (SaaS) cloud banking platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Payments Hub solution into a number of territories including Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore, marking the first time the platform will be available to customers in Asia. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-102325-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" /><p><a href="https://mambu.com/en">Mambu</a>, a global software as a service (SaaS) cloud banking platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Payments Hub solution into a number of territories including Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore, marking the first time the platform will be available to customers in Asia. </p>
<p>The expansion builds on strong adoption of Mambu Payments Hub by banks and fintechs operating across multiple payment schemes and jurisdictions and further broadens the portfolio of Mambu Payment solutions available in Asia, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>Mambu Payments Hub is a cloud-native, API-first payments orchestration platform designed to help financial institutions manage and process payments across multiple schemes and rails from a single system. </p>
<p>With the Mambu Payments Hub financial institutions can also build, launch and scale payment offerings faster and at lower cost, while ensuring regulatory compliance.</p>
<p>With Mambu’s Payments Hub, financial institutions can centralize payment operations through a scalable, event-driven platform; streamline payment processing, liquidity management and reconciliations across schemes and markets; scale securely via an API-first cloud platform that grows with demand; accelerate time-to-market when onboarding new banking partners (up to 6x faster) and connecting to new schemes; reduce operational overhead by minimizing manual tasks and file handling.</p>
<p>“The payments landscape in Asia is transforming at unprecedented speed, driven by rising demand for instant, seamless and embedded payment experiences. To enable banks and fintechs to seize this opportunity we are bringing Mambu’s Payments Hub to Asia, </p>
<p>&#8220;Mambu’s Payments Hub provides a modern, cloud-native platform that enables the orchestration of multiple payment rails, real-time payment processing, and the build and scaling of new payment solutions more quickly and efficiently and all on a single system,&#8221; said David Becker, Managing Director, Head of Asia Pacific (APAC) Sales at Mambu.</p>
<p>Mambu said it continues to expand connectivity to major payment rails worldwide, enabling financial institutions to support both established and emerging schemes through a single platform. </p>
<p>This expansion marks the next phase of Mambu’s international growth, as it continues to build global core banking and payments infrastructure that empowers fast-growing financial institutions to scale globally while remaining compliant and agile locally.</p>
<p>“Payments are becoming more global and more local, more interconnected and more fragmented, and now move in real-time,</p>
<p>&#8220;This complexity makes scaling payments across multiple markets challenging,&#8221; said Edouard Mandon, Vice President Payments at Mambu.</p>
<p>To solve this, he said the firm has expanded its payments hub to give institutions access to local schemes while maintaining a consistent integration and operational experience. </p>
<p>&#8220;This continues our investment in connectivity at scale, which increasingly includes next-generation rails, to deliver payment solutions truly built for the future,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>According to the statement, Mambu Payments Hub is already being deployed by leading global financial institutions around the world including Western Union, BCB Group, Flowe and Spendesk, where it is being used to support payment flows at scale and underpinning expansion into new regions.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dKDbrUePvH"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/trufin-secures-strategic-investment-led-by-singapore-based-sc-ventures/">TruFin secures strategic investment led by Singapore-based SC Ventures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;TruFin secures strategic investment led by Singapore-based SC Ventures&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/trufin-secures-strategic-investment-led-by-singapore-based-sc-ventures/embed/#?secret=1KSOs0Csnu#?secret=dKDbrUePvH" data-secret="dKDbrUePvH" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Grove’s ICON1C raises $7.92M from community and collaborators for expansion, acquisitions</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/patrick-groves-icon1c-raises-7-92m-from-community-and-collaborators-for-expansion-acquisitions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ICON1C]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117391</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />ICON1C, a Singapore-based investment and operating platform focused on building businesses in the global premium experience economy, announced Thursday it has raised S$10 million ($7.92 million) from its stakeholders and members to accelerate its expansion and for acquisitions.
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>ICON1C, a Singapore-based investment and operating platform focused on building businesses in the global premium experience economy, announced Thursday it has raised S$10 million ($7.92 million) from its stakeholders and members to accelerate its expansion and for acquisitions.</p>
<p>ICON1C said in a statement that the funding round was deliberately raised from its stakeholders and members rather than traditional institutions.</p>
<p>Approximately 20 long-standing clients have joined as partners, reflecting deep alignment between the group and the communities it serves.</p>
<p>The proceeds from the raise will be used to execute targeted merger and acquisitions (M&amp;A) across the premium experience economy, prioritizing profitable and cash-generative businesses; strengthen ICON1C’s central platform capabilities to support scalable, long-term growth; expand flagship brands into new global locations.</p>
<p>ICON1C operates with a disciplined platform model focused on profitability first, selective M&amp;A, and long-term capital compounding — a structure designed to scale efficiently across geographies and categories.</p>
<p>The group expects to complete five to six additional acquisitions over the coming 24 months, as it works toward a potential initial public offering (IPO) on a global stock exchange in the medium term.</p>
<p>“We are seeing a structural, multi-decade shift in consumer behavior. People are increasingly choosing connection, community, and real-world experiences over physical goods,</p>
<p>&#8220;ICON1C exists to own and compound the best of those experiences globally—profitably, and at scale,&#8221; said Patrick Grove, Co-Founder and Executive Chairman of ICON1C.</p>
<p>“We didn’t raise capital out of necessity. We raised it because we wanted collaborators,</p>
<p>&#8220;Our members understand our brands, our standards, and our long-term vision. That alignment is invaluable as we enter the next phase of growth,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Founded in early 2025, ICON1C was established with an ambition to build a modern house of brands across live events, hospitality, private members’ clubs, wellness, and experiential lifestyle assets.</p>
<p>The group’s foundation brands include Amber Lounge and Mandala Club, and it recently acquired the brand of members club, 1880.</p>
<p>“Luxury has evolved from what you own to what you experience—and who you experience it with. The most valuable experiences today create memory, community, and purpose anchored in real places,</p>
<p>&#8220;ICON1C exists to partner with founders pursuing this vision, by helping them scale globally without diluting what makes their brands special,&#8221; said Ben Jones, Co-Founder of ICON1C and Founder of Mandala Group.</p>
<p>ICON1C actively partners with founders and operators of established, cash-generative experience businesses seeking a long-term home, operational support, and access to a broader global ecosystem while preserving brand identity and culture.</p>
<p>The firm’s portfolio includes Amber Lounge, the world’s most exclusive Formula 1 after-party for UHNW clientele, global brand partners and leaders; and Mandala Club, Singapore’s leading private members’ club.</p>
<p>ICON1C also operates across Monaco, Singapore, and Abu Dhabi, with additional geographies and brands expected to be announced in the coming months.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="55tN4WYhWe"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/">Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/embed/#?secret=vQGGXtndCC#?secret=55tN4WYhWe" data-secret="55tN4WYhWe" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P upgrades Grab to ‘BB’ on improving earnings quality</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/sp-upgrades-grab-to-bb-on-improving-earnings-quality/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 01:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Grab]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117388</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />S&#38;P Global Ratings has on Wednesday upgraded Grab Holdings to 'BB' from 'BB-' on improving earnings quality with positive outlook. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>S&amp;P Global Ratings has on Wednesday upgraded <a href="https://www.grab.com/sg/">Grab Holdings</a> to &#8216;BB&#8217; from &#8216;BB-&#8216; on improving earnings quality with positive outlook. </p>
<p>The rating agency said in a note that it expects Grab to improve its earnings quality over the next 12-18 months because it will remain dominant in Southeast Asia&#8217;s mobility and delivery industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe the cash position of the Singapore-based company will become more robust owing to higher operating leverage and disciplined spending on growth,&#8221; it said. </p>
<p>The positive outlook also reflects its expectation that Grab will maintain its dominant position as Southeast Asia&#8217;s top mobility and deliveries platform operator over the next 12-18 months.</p>
<p>It is noted that Grab has established a record of leadership in the mobility and deliveries sectors in key Southeast Asia markets. </p>
<p>This, along with a rise in Grab&#8217;s recurring user base and less-aggressive competition, will boost its business position.</p>
<p>S&amp;P expects Grab to maintain its on-demand take rate at 13 percent to 15 percent in 2026 and 2027, versus 13.6 percent in 2025.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s food delivery and mobility segment should grow steadily in 2026 and 2027, in its view. </p>
<p>&#8220;Grab will also continue to invest in financial services, particularly in digital banking, during this period, </p>
<p>&#8220;That said, we expect financial services&#8217; contribution to Grab&#8217;s revenues to remain modest,&#8221; it noted.  </p>
<p>It forecasts the company&#8217;s revenue will grow 20 percent in 2026 to $4.1 billion, and about 10 percent annually thereafter.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, S&amp;P said Grab&#8217;s earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) margin will continue to improve, reflecting operating efficiencies and greater economies of scale. </p>
<p>Profitability metrics will also improve as Grab&#8217;s financial services business achieves breakeven, likely by the end of 2026. </p>
<p>&#8220;We forecast its EBITDA margin at 17 percent to 18 percent in 2026 and 2027, compared with 11.2 percent in 2024, and our estimate of about 17.3 percent in 2025,&#8221; said the rating agency. </p>
<p>It believes Grab will maintain a sufficient financial cushion, considering an unrestricted cash balance of about $6.6 billion as of end-2025. </p>
<p>&#8220;This is because we anticipate the company will generate positive free cash flows since its mobility and delivery services businesses have low investment requirements,&#8221; it explained.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P also expects Grab to direct a proportion of its cash flows to its financial services business.</p>
<p>In its base case, S&amp;P expects Grab&#8217;s ratio of debt to EBITDA to trend closer to 3 times by 2027, from about 4 times in 2025. </p>
<p>An expanding earnings base and limited external debt will lead to steady improvement in the company&#8217;s credit metrics, it added. </p>
<p>S&amp;P does not net-off Grab&#8217;s available cash surplus against gross debt because it believes maintaining a sizable cash surplus allows players like the company to be nimble and meet any sudden investment requirements. </p>
<p>This also considers Grab&#8217;s financial services business, which has a short track record and is yet to demonstrate asset quality over a long economic cycle and in different markets. </p>
<p>However, it noted a fast-growing loan book and event risks could erode the company&#8217;s cash surplus and lead to volatility in credit metrics.</p>
<p>Having said that, S&amp;P does envisage a scenario wherein Grab&#8217;s credit metrics could strengthen beyond what is reflected in its base case. </p>
<p>&#8220;This could happen if (1) the company repays its $1.5 billion outstanding convertible bond, leading to a material reduction in gross debt and its debt-to-EBITDA ratio falls below 2 times sustainably; or (2) if we net-off Grab&#8217;s available cash surplus against debt, resulting in a net cash position in S&amp;P Global Ratings-adjusted terms, as its business position strengthens,&#8221; it explained. </p>
<p>S&amp;P expects Grab to maintain its measured approach toward potential acquisitions and shareholder distributions. </p>
<p>It estimates it will spend up to $600 million annually toward shareholder distributions and acquisitions in 2026 and 2027.</p>
<p>It is noted that Grab has recently acquired a 50.1 percent stake in Stash Financial, a U.S.-based digital investing platform. </p>
<p>This is Grab&#8217;s first material acquisition since its takeover of Uber Technologies Inc.&#8217;s southeast Asia business in 2018. </p>
<p>The company has also announced a $500 million share buyback program that we expect to be completed within 2026.</p>
<p>&#8220;However, should Grab consume its cash reserves for a large-scale acquisition or investment, we would reassess its business competitiveness and whether any incremental business improvement compensates for potentially higher leverage,&#8221; said S&amp;P.</p>
<p>Overall, the positive outlook reflects the rating agency&#8217;s expectation that Grab will maintain its dominant position as Southeast Asia&#8217;s top mobility and deliveries platform company over the next 12-18 months. </p>
<p>This will help the company maintain positive EBITDA and cash flows during this period. </p>
<p>&#8220;The outlook also reflects our view that Grab will maintain a conservative approach toward leverage management,&#8221; said S&amp;P. </p>
<p>It noted that it may revise the outlook back to stable if Grab&#8217;s EBITDA or cash flow starts to deteriorate, signaling a weakness in its business competitiveness. </p>
<p>This could happen because of heightened competition or Grab adopting more aggressive tactics to boost or defend market share.</p>
<p>A decline in gross merchandise value, take rate, or the number of monthly transacting users, or rising incentive spending could signal such deterioration, said S&amp;P.  </p>
<p>A material reduction in the company&#8217;s liquidity buffer could also put downside pressure on the rating.</p>
<p>&#8220;We could raise the rating if Grab continues to strengthen its operational competitiveness, improves its EBITDA, operating cash flow, and profitability, and also keeps leverage at a prudent level, </p>
<p>&#8220;The debt-to-EBITDA ratio remaining below 2 times on a sustained basis could indicate such improvement,&#8221; it added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2wCNYM3131"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/12/grab-posts-first-full-year-net-profit-with-20-percent-revenue-growth/">Grab posts first full year net profit with 20 percent revenue growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Grab posts first full year net profit with 20 percent revenue growth&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/12/grab-posts-first-full-year-net-profit-with-20-percent-revenue-growth/embed/#?secret=OPHTvfFpxK#?secret=2wCNYM3131" data-secret="2wCNYM3131" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Milestone Systems]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117357</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Milestone Systems, a global data-driven video technology, announced Wednesday the opening of its new Experience Center in Singapore, representing a major expansion of the company’s regional footprint in Asia. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.milestonesys.com/">Milestone Systems</a>, a global data-driven video technology firm, announced Wednesday the opening of its new Experience Center in Singapore, representing a major expansion of the company’s regional footprint in Asia. </p>
<p>The firm said in a statement that the center will serve as a next-generation hub for solution design, cross-industry collaboration, and real-world testing of video innovations enabled by data analytics, hybrid-cloud architectures, and artificial intelligence (AI). </p>
<p>It directly complements the Singapore government’s national agenda, announced at 2026 Budget by Singapore&#8217;s Prime Minister Lawrence Wong, by creating a stronger foundation for safe, industry-ready AI adoption in critical sectors.</p>
<p>The new facility underscores Milestone’s long-term commitment to Asia and supports the region’s rapid transition toward intelligent, automated and increasingly interconnected operational environments. </p>
<p>It is designed to help governments, enterprises, and critical infrastructure operators accelerate deployments of video-driven solutions that enhance safety, efficiency, and resilience while ensuring that innovation aligns with global standards of responsible AI adoption.</p>
<p>“Asia is the world’s most dynamic security and smart infrastructure market, and enterprises are expecting deeper operational intelligence and more adaptable system architectures,</p>
<p>“Our expanded Singapore hub gives the region the capabilities, collaboration space, and expertise required to address these new opportunities and scale innovation,&#8221; said Kiean Khoo, Asia Business Head, Milestone Systems.</p>
<p>It is noted that Asian growth in demand for intelligent video and integrated security solutions is being driven by rapid urbanization, infrastructure expansion, and rising expectations for real-time operational insights across airports, transport hubs, hospitality, critical infrastructure, and public spaces.</p>
<p>“Our expanded presence in Singapore reflects two clear realities: the scale and pace of demand across Asia, and the importance of scaling through open ecosystems and responsible innovation,</p>
<p>&#8220;The Experience Center will play a pivotal role in helping partners and customers build AI-enabled solutions that are trustworthy, interoperable and ready for real-world complexities,&#8221; said Morten Illum, Chief Revenue Officer, Milestone Systems.</p>
<p>According to the statement, the Asia-Pacific Physical Security Market size is estimated at $42.25 billion in 2025, and is expected to reach $59.54 billion by 2030, at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 7.1 percent during the forecast period (2025-2030).</p>
<p>It is increasingly defined by intelligent video, access control, and integrated security solutions. </p>
<p>Market trends show a significant migration from legacy CCTV systems to IP-based, hybrid, and cloud-enabled platforms, with an emphasis on interoperability, analytics, and AI-driven decision-making.</p>
<p>“As the region accelerates into the AI-era, our customers are looking for trusted, high- quality data to power autonomous decision-making, </p>
<p>“The new Experience Center is built to help organizations validate AI-driven workflows safely and responsibly. It lets businesses experiment, optimize and innovate with the confidence that their systems meet the highest standards of governance, transparency and human oversight,&#8221; Khoo added.</p>
<p>As organizations adopt AI—systems capable of planning, the firm highlighted that reasoning and autonomously executing tasks—video technology is becoming a core source of trusted, high-value data. </p>
<p>The Asia Experience Center, therefore, will act as a proving ground for businesses seeking to explore how video, sensors, and multimodal data can be integrated to support e.g. AI agents in performing complex operational workflows.</p>
<p>The center features an expanded environment for scenario testing, multi-vendor integration, and modelling of high-density, real-time environments such as airports, urban transport, critical infrastructure, manufacturing floors, retail ecosystems, hospitality facilities and smart city districts. </p>
<p>It can evaluate how AI workflows interact with real operational conditions, including video quality, data continuity, cybersecurity controls, and compliance requirements.</p>
<p>“Milestone Systems is deepening its role as a catalyst for innovation across the region’s evolving security and smart-infrastructure landscape with the launch of the Asia Experience Center, </p>
<p>&#8220;By combining open-platform video technology, responsible AI principles, and a strong partner ecosystem, the center will help accelerate Asia’s transition toward safer, smarter and more data-driven environments,&#8221; Illum added.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6HFCmudlUc"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/singtels-digital-infraco-accelerates-sovereign-ai-innovations-with-center-of-excellence-for-applied-ai-with-nvidia/">Singtel’s Digital InfraCo accelerates sovereign AI innovations with Center of Excellence for Applied AI with NVIDIA</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Singtel’s Digital InfraCo accelerates sovereign AI innovations with Center of Excellence for Applied AI with NVIDIA&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/singtels-digital-infraco-accelerates-sovereign-ai-innovations-with-center-of-excellence-for-applied-ai-with-nvidia/embed/#?secret=Iy11AniChG#?secret=6HFCmudlUc" data-secret="6HFCmudlUc" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
