<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
    <atom:link href="https://technode.global/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
    <description>Latest news and trends about tech</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-technode-icon-2020_512x512-32x32.png</url>
      <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Realty]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117405</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Digital Realty, the global cloud- and carrier-neutral data center platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Digital Realty Innovation Lab (DRIL) into Singapore, Japan and London. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-08-182851-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.digitalrealty.com/">Digital Realty</a>, the global cloud- and carrier-neutral data center platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Digital Realty Innovation Lab (DRIL) into Singapore, Japan and London. </p>
<p>This marks the first expansion of the company’s global DRIL network into Asia Pacific and Europe, following the successful launch of the inaugural DRIL facility in Northern Virginia in September 2025, which has received acclaim from enterprise customers, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>The new DRIL locations will offer the firm&#8217;s ecosystem of partners and customers fully supported, real-world testing environments where they can bring their own workloads or use pre-configured infrastructure to validate AI and hybrid cloud deployments before scaling. </p>
<p>This is especially important as AI adoption increases and infrastructure readiness has emerged as a critical barrier to moving from experimentation to production at scale. </p>
<p>All three are expected to be available for use by customers and partners this year.</p>
<p>The launch represents Digital Realty’s commitment to support Singapore, Japan and the United Kingdom’s continued leadership in artificial intelligence (AI) innovation. </p>
<p>In Singapore, AI adoption is driving continued growth in the nation’s digital economy, which now accounts for 18.6 percent of total gross domestic product (GDP). </p>
<p>Japan also plans to invest 10 trillion yen ($64.12 billion) or more in the semiconductor and AI sectors by 2030. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the United Kingdom’s AI sector continues to accelerate, with more than 5,800 AI companies now operating nationwide, sector revenue reaching £23.9 billion ($32.42 billion) and AI generating £11.8 billion ($16 billion) in gross value added (GVA).</p>
<p>According to the statement, the Singapore DRIL is designed to serve as a digital innovation hub, bringing together local customers, partners, and research institutions with global technology providers and industry participants seeking to develop, test and deploy AI and hybrid cloud solutions in Singapore.</p>
<p>In Japan, the DRIL will be located at the company’s NRT12 data center in the Greater Tokyo area. </p>
<p>Designed to support advanced AI and high-performance computing use cases, it will feature 20 racks with direct liquid cooling (DLC) capabilities, enabling support for high-power-density workloads.</p>
<p>The DRIL in the UK will be in London, providing customers and partners with a dedicated environment to test and validate AI and hybrid cloud deployments before full-scale implementation.</p>
<p>“Sustaining rapidly expanding digital economies requires innovation ecosystems built on infrastructure that is not only AI-ready, but also efficient, resilient, and trusted,” said Serene Nah, Managing Director and Head of Asia Pacific, Digital Realty.</p>
<p>According to her, since launching the DRIL in the United States, they have seen strong demand from customers and partners across Asia Pacific seeking dedicated environments to validate AI and hybrid cloud architectures before deploying at scale. </p>
<p>&#8220;Bringing this capability to Singapore and Japan reflects the digital maturity of these markets and their critical role in shaping the region&#8217;s long-term digital competitiveness, </p>
<p>&#8220;By creating spaces where enterprises can test, optimize, and de-risk their AI infrastructure, we&#8217;re accelerating responsible deployment and strengthening Asia Pacific&#8217;s position as a hub for trusted digital innovation,&#8221; she added. </p>
<p>Séamus Dunne, Managing Director, UK &amp; Ireland, Digital Realty, said European AI adoption is expected to grow rapidly, and London sits at the center of that growth.</p>
<p>“Launching the Digital Realty Innovation Lab in London gives enterprises and partners a real-world environment to validate AI and hybrid cloud architectures before rolling them out across live environments, </p>
<p>&#8220;It’s a critical step in helping organizations deploy next-generation infrastructure faster, and with greater confidence,” he added. </p>
<p>The new DRIL locations will enable businesses throughout Asia Pacific and Europe to test performance, optimize configurations, and seamlessly connect to cloud and network providers via ServiceFabric, Digital Realty’s global interconnection and orchestration platform.</p>
<p>By leveraging Digital Realty’s global experience in deploying AI-ready infrastructure and its proven Pervasive Datacenter Architecture (PDx) methodology, the DRIL enables customers to test, optimize, and validate AI deployments in real-world conditions, reducing complexity and significantly accelerating the journey from pilot to production.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="qXTWhYQycC"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/">IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/embed/#?secret=X1FGuVHHwu#?secret=qXTWhYQycC" data-secret="qXTWhYQycC" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFC invests $40M in Malaysia’s Zetrix AI to improve access to digital public infrastructure services</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ifc-invests-40m-in-malaysias-zetrix-ai-to-improve-access-to-digital-public-infrastructure-services/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:38:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Zetrix AI]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117402</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />The World Bank Group, through its private sector arm the International Finance Corporation (IFC), has announced a $40 million equity investment in Zetrix AI Berhad, to improve access to Digital Public Infrastructure (DPI) services in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-103823-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>The World Bank Group, through its private sector arm the International Finance Corporation (IFC), has announced a $40 million equity investment in <a href="https://www.zetrix.com/">Zetrix AI Berhad</a>, to improve access to Digital Public Infrastructure (DPI) services in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.</p>
<p>IFC said in a statement on Wednesday that the investment will support the development and rollout of new, blockchain-based DPI applications and artificial intelligence (AI)-enabled products that aim to improve digital inclusion, access to services, and economic efficiency in Malaysia and the broader ASEAN region. </p>
<p>In Malaysia, these new services would integrate with the country’s digital ecosystem through MyDigital ID, the country’s digital identity system, and the Malaysia Blockchain Infrastructure (MBI), the country’s national blockchain service network. </p>
<p>Zetrix AI’s DPI applications and products aim to make a range of services more efficient, secure, and cost-effective, including the verification of digital IDs through to the digitalization of international trade and the tokenization of real-world assets, among others. </p>
<p>The investment will also support Zetrix AI’s expansion of its DPI services into emerging markets in ASEAN and the rest of the world. </p>
<p>“This investment reflects IFC’s commitment to advancing Malaysia’s digital transformation agenda, in line with the Thirteenth Malaysia Plan, 2026-2030,</p>
<p>“The development of Digital Public Infrastructure services is essential to improving public service delivery, strengthening economic competitiveness, and ensuring that growth is inclusive and sustainable,&#8221; said Judith Green, World Bank Group Country Manager for Malaysia. </p>
<p>She also said the investments like this allow them to scale innovative digital solutions and support the creation of resilient, secure and interoperable systems that expand access to services and opportunities for both people and businesses in Malaysia and emerging markets in the broader ASEAN region and beyond.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, TS Wong, Group Managing Director of Zetrix AI, said from digital IDs to digitized customs clearance processing to large language models and stable coins, the real-world cross-border use cases in blockchain and AI that they are deploying are aimed at catalyzing disruptive transformation across ASEAN and enabling deeper socio-economic integration in the region.</p>
<p>“With the participation and market access from IFC, we will accelerate our global expansion plans,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>Headquartered in Malaysia, Zetrix AI, formerly known as MY E.G. Services Berhad, started operations in 2000 as a firm in the provision of electronic government services and complementary commercial offerings in Malaysia. </p>
<p>The firm is currently deploying blockchain technology and AI in supporting the public and private sectors across ASEAN.</p>
<p>It is leveraging its Layer-1 blockchain platform Zetrix and the convergence of Web3, AI and robotics to enable optimally-efficient, intelligent and secure cross-border transactions, digital identity interoperability and automation solutions that connect people, businesses and governments.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="P0aYj9fXCU"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/11/12/zetrix-ai-partners-fmff-to-boost-digitalization-of-cross-border-trade-through-ztrade/">Zetrix AI partners FMFF to boost digitalization of cross-border trade through ZTrade</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Zetrix AI partners FMFF to boost digitalization of cross-border trade through ZTrade&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/11/12/zetrix-ai-partners-fmff-to-boost-digitalization-of-cross-border-trade-through-ztrade/embed/#?secret=sPearsrjGo#?secret=P0aYj9fXCU" data-secret="P0aYj9fXCU" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mambu expands payments hub into Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/mambu-expands-payments-hub-into-indonesia-the-philippines-malaysia-and-singapore/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Philippines]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117397</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-102325-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" />Mambu, a global software as a service (SaaS) cloud banking platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Payments Hub solution into a number of territories including Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore, marking the first time the platform will be available to customers in Asia. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-102325-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" /><p><a href="https://mambu.com/en">Mambu</a>, a global software as a service (SaaS) cloud banking platform, announced Wednesday the expansion of its Payments Hub solution into a number of territories including Indonesia, the Philippines, Malaysia and Singapore, marking the first time the platform will be available to customers in Asia. </p>
<p>The expansion builds on strong adoption of Mambu Payments Hub by banks and fintechs operating across multiple payment schemes and jurisdictions and further broadens the portfolio of Mambu Payment solutions available in Asia, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>Mambu Payments Hub is a cloud-native, API-first payments orchestration platform designed to help financial institutions manage and process payments across multiple schemes and rails from a single system. </p>
<p>With the Mambu Payments Hub financial institutions can also build, launch and scale payment offerings faster and at lower cost, while ensuring regulatory compliance.</p>
<p>With Mambu’s Payments Hub, financial institutions can centralize payment operations through a scalable, event-driven platform; streamline payment processing, liquidity management and reconciliations across schemes and markets; scale securely via an API-first cloud platform that grows with demand; accelerate time-to-market when onboarding new banking partners (up to 6x faster) and connecting to new schemes; reduce operational overhead by minimizing manual tasks and file handling.</p>
<p>“The payments landscape in Asia is transforming at unprecedented speed, driven by rising demand for instant, seamless and embedded payment experiences. To enable banks and fintechs to seize this opportunity we are bringing Mambu’s Payments Hub to Asia, </p>
<p>&#8220;Mambu’s Payments Hub provides a modern, cloud-native platform that enables the orchestration of multiple payment rails, real-time payment processing, and the build and scaling of new payment solutions more quickly and efficiently and all on a single system,&#8221; said David Becker, Managing Director, Head of Asia Pacific (APAC) Sales at Mambu.</p>
<p>Mambu said it continues to expand connectivity to major payment rails worldwide, enabling financial institutions to support both established and emerging schemes through a single platform. </p>
<p>This expansion marks the next phase of Mambu’s international growth, as it continues to build global core banking and payments infrastructure that empowers fast-growing financial institutions to scale globally while remaining compliant and agile locally.</p>
<p>“Payments are becoming more global and more local, more interconnected and more fragmented, and now move in real-time,</p>
<p>&#8220;This complexity makes scaling payments across multiple markets challenging,&#8221; said Edouard Mandon, Vice President Payments at Mambu.</p>
<p>To solve this, he said the firm has expanded its payments hub to give institutions access to local schemes while maintaining a consistent integration and operational experience. </p>
<p>&#8220;This continues our investment in connectivity at scale, which increasingly includes next-generation rails, to deliver payment solutions truly built for the future,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>According to the statement, Mambu Payments Hub is already being deployed by leading global financial institutions around the world including Western Union, BCB Group, Flowe and Spendesk, where it is being used to support payment flows at scale and underpinning expansion into new regions.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="dKDbrUePvH"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/trufin-secures-strategic-investment-led-by-singapore-based-sc-ventures/">TruFin secures strategic investment led by Singapore-based SC Ventures</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;TruFin secures strategic investment led by Singapore-based SC Ventures&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/trufin-secures-strategic-investment-led-by-singapore-based-sc-ventures/embed/#?secret=1KSOs0Csnu#?secret=dKDbrUePvH" data-secret="dKDbrUePvH" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patrick Grove’s ICON1C raises $7.92M from community and collaborators for expansion, acquisitions</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/patrick-groves-icon1c-raises-7-92m-from-community-and-collaborators-for-expansion-acquisitions/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:14:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[ICON1C]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117391</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />ICON1C, a Singapore-based investment and operating platform focused on building businesses in the global premium experience economy, announced Thursday it has raised S$10 million ($7.92 million) from its stakeholders and members to accelerate its expansion and for acquisitions.
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-26-101349-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>ICON1C, a Singapore-based investment and operating platform focused on building businesses in the global premium experience economy, announced Thursday it has raised S$10 million ($7.92 million) from its stakeholders and members to accelerate its expansion and for acquisitions.</p>
<p>ICON1C said in a statement that the funding round was deliberately raised from its stakeholders and members rather than traditional institutions.</p>
<p>Approximately 20 long-standing clients have joined as partners, reflecting deep alignment between the group and the communities it serves.</p>
<p>The proceeds from the raise will be used to execute targeted merger and acquisitions (M&amp;A) across the premium experience economy, prioritizing profitable and cash-generative businesses; strengthen ICON1C’s central platform capabilities to support scalable, long-term growth; expand flagship brands into new global locations.</p>
<p>ICON1C operates with a disciplined platform model focused on profitability first, selective M&amp;A, and long-term capital compounding — a structure designed to scale efficiently across geographies and categories.</p>
<p>The group expects to complete five to six additional acquisitions over the coming 24 months, as it works toward a potential initial public offering (IPO) on a global stock exchange in the medium term.</p>
<p>“We are seeing a structural, multi-decade shift in consumer behavior. People are increasingly choosing connection, community, and real-world experiences over physical goods,</p>
<p>&#8220;ICON1C exists to own and compound the best of those experiences globally—profitably, and at scale,&#8221; said Patrick Grove, Co-Founder and Executive Chairman of ICON1C.</p>
<p>“We didn’t raise capital out of necessity. We raised it because we wanted collaborators,</p>
<p>&#8220;Our members understand our brands, our standards, and our long-term vision. That alignment is invaluable as we enter the next phase of growth,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Founded in early 2025, ICON1C was established with an ambition to build a modern house of brands across live events, hospitality, private members’ clubs, wellness, and experiential lifestyle assets.</p>
<p>The group’s foundation brands include Amber Lounge and Mandala Club, and it recently acquired the brand of members club, 1880.</p>
<p>“Luxury has evolved from what you own to what you experience—and who you experience it with. The most valuable experiences today create memory, community, and purpose anchored in real places,</p>
<p>&#8220;ICON1C exists to partner with founders pursuing this vision, by helping them scale globally without diluting what makes their brands special,&#8221; said Ben Jones, Co-Founder of ICON1C and Founder of Mandala Group.</p>
<p>ICON1C actively partners with founders and operators of established, cash-generative experience businesses seeking a long-term home, operational support, and access to a broader global ecosystem while preserving brand identity and culture.</p>
<p>The firm’s portfolio includes Amber Lounge, the world’s most exclusive Formula 1 after-party for UHNW clientele, global brand partners and leaders; and Mandala Club, Singapore’s leading private members’ club.</p>
<p>ICON1C also operates across Monaco, Singapore, and Abu Dhabi, with additional geographies and brands expected to be announced in the coming months.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="55tN4WYhWe"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/">Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/embed/#?secret=vQGGXtndCC#?secret=55tN4WYhWe" data-secret="55tN4WYhWe" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&amp;P upgrades Grab to ‘BB’ on improving earnings quality</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/26/sp-upgrades-grab-to-bb-on-improving-earnings-quality/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 01:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Grab]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117388</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />S&#38;P Global Ratings has on Wednesday upgraded Grab Holdings to 'BB' from 'BB-' on improving earnings quality with positive outlook. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/Screenshot-2025-06-11-152500-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>S&amp;P Global Ratings has on Wednesday upgraded <a href="https://www.grab.com/sg/">Grab Holdings</a> to &#8216;BB&#8217; from &#8216;BB-&#8216; on improving earnings quality with positive outlook. </p>
<p>The rating agency said in a note that it expects Grab to improve its earnings quality over the next 12-18 months because it will remain dominant in Southeast Asia&#8217;s mobility and delivery industry.</p>
<p>&#8220;We believe the cash position of the Singapore-based company will become more robust owing to higher operating leverage and disciplined spending on growth,&#8221; it said. </p>
<p>The positive outlook also reflects its expectation that Grab will maintain its dominant position as Southeast Asia&#8217;s top mobility and deliveries platform operator over the next 12-18 months.</p>
<p>It is noted that Grab has established a record of leadership in the mobility and deliveries sectors in key Southeast Asia markets. </p>
<p>This, along with a rise in Grab&#8217;s recurring user base and less-aggressive competition, will boost its business position.</p>
<p>S&amp;P expects Grab to maintain its on-demand take rate at 13 percent to 15 percent in 2026 and 2027, versus 13.6 percent in 2025.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s food delivery and mobility segment should grow steadily in 2026 and 2027, in its view. </p>
<p>&#8220;Grab will also continue to invest in financial services, particularly in digital banking, during this period, </p>
<p>&#8220;That said, we expect financial services&#8217; contribution to Grab&#8217;s revenues to remain modest,&#8221; it noted.  </p>
<p>It forecasts the company&#8217;s revenue will grow 20 percent in 2026 to $4.1 billion, and about 10 percent annually thereafter.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, S&amp;P said Grab&#8217;s earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) margin will continue to improve, reflecting operating efficiencies and greater economies of scale. </p>
<p>Profitability metrics will also improve as Grab&#8217;s financial services business achieves breakeven, likely by the end of 2026. </p>
<p>&#8220;We forecast its EBITDA margin at 17 percent to 18 percent in 2026 and 2027, compared with 11.2 percent in 2024, and our estimate of about 17.3 percent in 2025,&#8221; said the rating agency. </p>
<p>It believes Grab will maintain a sufficient financial cushion, considering an unrestricted cash balance of about $6.6 billion as of end-2025. </p>
<p>&#8220;This is because we anticipate the company will generate positive free cash flows since its mobility and delivery services businesses have low investment requirements,&#8221; it explained.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P also expects Grab to direct a proportion of its cash flows to its financial services business.</p>
<p>In its base case, S&amp;P expects Grab&#8217;s ratio of debt to EBITDA to trend closer to 3 times by 2027, from about 4 times in 2025. </p>
<p>An expanding earnings base and limited external debt will lead to steady improvement in the company&#8217;s credit metrics, it added. </p>
<p>S&amp;P does not net-off Grab&#8217;s available cash surplus against gross debt because it believes maintaining a sizable cash surplus allows players like the company to be nimble and meet any sudden investment requirements. </p>
<p>This also considers Grab&#8217;s financial services business, which has a short track record and is yet to demonstrate asset quality over a long economic cycle and in different markets. </p>
<p>However, it noted a fast-growing loan book and event risks could erode the company&#8217;s cash surplus and lead to volatility in credit metrics.</p>
<p>Having said that, S&amp;P does envisage a scenario wherein Grab&#8217;s credit metrics could strengthen beyond what is reflected in its base case. </p>
<p>&#8220;This could happen if (1) the company repays its $1.5 billion outstanding convertible bond, leading to a material reduction in gross debt and its debt-to-EBITDA ratio falls below 2 times sustainably; or (2) if we net-off Grab&#8217;s available cash surplus against debt, resulting in a net cash position in S&amp;P Global Ratings-adjusted terms, as its business position strengthens,&#8221; it explained. </p>
<p>S&amp;P expects Grab to maintain its measured approach toward potential acquisitions and shareholder distributions. </p>
<p>It estimates it will spend up to $600 million annually toward shareholder distributions and acquisitions in 2026 and 2027.</p>
<p>It is noted that Grab has recently acquired a 50.1 percent stake in Stash Financial, a U.S.-based digital investing platform. </p>
<p>This is Grab&#8217;s first material acquisition since its takeover of Uber Technologies Inc.&#8217;s southeast Asia business in 2018. </p>
<p>The company has also announced a $500 million share buyback program that we expect to be completed within 2026.</p>
<p>&#8220;However, should Grab consume its cash reserves for a large-scale acquisition or investment, we would reassess its business competitiveness and whether any incremental business improvement compensates for potentially higher leverage,&#8221; said S&amp;P.</p>
<p>Overall, the positive outlook reflects the rating agency&#8217;s expectation that Grab will maintain its dominant position as Southeast Asia&#8217;s top mobility and deliveries platform company over the next 12-18 months. </p>
<p>This will help the company maintain positive EBITDA and cash flows during this period. </p>
<p>&#8220;The outlook also reflects our view that Grab will maintain a conservative approach toward leverage management,&#8221; said S&amp;P. </p>
<p>It noted that it may revise the outlook back to stable if Grab&#8217;s EBITDA or cash flow starts to deteriorate, signaling a weakness in its business competitiveness. </p>
<p>This could happen because of heightened competition or Grab adopting more aggressive tactics to boost or defend market share.</p>
<p>A decline in gross merchandise value, take rate, or the number of monthly transacting users, or rising incentive spending could signal such deterioration, said S&amp;P.  </p>
<p>A material reduction in the company&#8217;s liquidity buffer could also put downside pressure on the rating.</p>
<p>&#8220;We could raise the rating if Grab continues to strengthen its operational competitiveness, improves its EBITDA, operating cash flow, and profitability, and also keeps leverage at a prudent level, </p>
<p>&#8220;The debt-to-EBITDA ratio remaining below 2 times on a sustained basis could indicate such improvement,&#8221; it added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2wCNYM3131"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/12/grab-posts-first-full-year-net-profit-with-20-percent-revenue-growth/">Grab posts first full year net profit with 20 percent revenue growth</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Grab posts first full year net profit with 20 percent revenue growth&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/12/grab-posts-first-full-year-net-profit-with-20-percent-revenue-growth/embed/#?secret=OPHTvfFpxK#?secret=2wCNYM3131" data-secret="2wCNYM3131" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Milestone Systems expands Singapore footprint with the launch of Asia Experience Center</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/milestone-systems-expands-singapore-footprint-with-the-launch-of-asia-experience-center/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:31:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Milestone Systems]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117357</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Milestone Systems, a global data-driven video technology, announced Wednesday the opening of its new Experience Center in Singapore, representing a major expansion of the company’s regional footprint in Asia. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Photo_Milestone-Systems-Singapore-Experience-Centre-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.milestonesys.com/">Milestone Systems</a>, a global data-driven video technology firm, announced Wednesday the opening of its new Experience Center in Singapore, representing a major expansion of the company’s regional footprint in Asia. </p>
<p>The firm said in a statement that the center will serve as a next-generation hub for solution design, cross-industry collaboration, and real-world testing of video innovations enabled by data analytics, hybrid-cloud architectures, and artificial intelligence (AI). </p>
<p>It directly complements the Singapore government’s national agenda, announced at 2026 Budget by Singapore&#8217;s Prime Minister Lawrence Wong, by creating a stronger foundation for safe, industry-ready AI adoption in critical sectors.</p>
<p>The new facility underscores Milestone’s long-term commitment to Asia and supports the region’s rapid transition toward intelligent, automated and increasingly interconnected operational environments. </p>
<p>It is designed to help governments, enterprises, and critical infrastructure operators accelerate deployments of video-driven solutions that enhance safety, efficiency, and resilience while ensuring that innovation aligns with global standards of responsible AI adoption.</p>
<p>“Asia is the world’s most dynamic security and smart infrastructure market, and enterprises are expecting deeper operational intelligence and more adaptable system architectures,</p>
<p>“Our expanded Singapore hub gives the region the capabilities, collaboration space, and expertise required to address these new opportunities and scale innovation,&#8221; said Kiean Khoo, Asia Business Head, Milestone Systems.</p>
<p>It is noted that Asian growth in demand for intelligent video and integrated security solutions is being driven by rapid urbanization, infrastructure expansion, and rising expectations for real-time operational insights across airports, transport hubs, hospitality, critical infrastructure, and public spaces.</p>
<p>“Our expanded presence in Singapore reflects two clear realities: the scale and pace of demand across Asia, and the importance of scaling through open ecosystems and responsible innovation,</p>
<p>&#8220;The Experience Center will play a pivotal role in helping partners and customers build AI-enabled solutions that are trustworthy, interoperable and ready for real-world complexities,&#8221; said Morten Illum, Chief Revenue Officer, Milestone Systems.</p>
<p>According to the statement, the Asia-Pacific Physical Security Market size is estimated at $42.25 billion in 2025, and is expected to reach $59.54 billion by 2030, at a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 7.1 percent during the forecast period (2025-2030).</p>
<p>It is increasingly defined by intelligent video, access control, and integrated security solutions. </p>
<p>Market trends show a significant migration from legacy CCTV systems to IP-based, hybrid, and cloud-enabled platforms, with an emphasis on interoperability, analytics, and AI-driven decision-making.</p>
<p>“As the region accelerates into the AI-era, our customers are looking for trusted, high- quality data to power autonomous decision-making, </p>
<p>“The new Experience Center is built to help organizations validate AI-driven workflows safely and responsibly. It lets businesses experiment, optimize and innovate with the confidence that their systems meet the highest standards of governance, transparency and human oversight,&#8221; Khoo added.</p>
<p>As organizations adopt AI—systems capable of planning, the firm highlighted that reasoning and autonomously executing tasks—video technology is becoming a core source of trusted, high-value data. </p>
<p>The Asia Experience Center, therefore, will act as a proving ground for businesses seeking to explore how video, sensors, and multimodal data can be integrated to support e.g. AI agents in performing complex operational workflows.</p>
<p>The center features an expanded environment for scenario testing, multi-vendor integration, and modelling of high-density, real-time environments such as airports, urban transport, critical infrastructure, manufacturing floors, retail ecosystems, hospitality facilities and smart city districts. </p>
<p>It can evaluate how AI workflows interact with real operational conditions, including video quality, data continuity, cybersecurity controls, and compliance requirements.</p>
<p>“Milestone Systems is deepening its role as a catalyst for innovation across the region’s evolving security and smart-infrastructure landscape with the launch of the Asia Experience Center, </p>
<p>&#8220;By combining open-platform video technology, responsible AI principles, and a strong partner ecosystem, the center will help accelerate Asia’s transition toward safer, smarter and more data-driven environments,&#8221; Illum added.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6HFCmudlUc"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/singtels-digital-infraco-accelerates-sovereign-ai-innovations-with-center-of-excellence-for-applied-ai-with-nvidia/">Singtel’s Digital InfraCo accelerates sovereign AI innovations with Center of Excellence for Applied AI with NVIDIA</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Singtel’s Digital InfraCo accelerates sovereign AI innovations with Center of Excellence for Applied AI with NVIDIA&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/25/singtels-digital-infraco-accelerates-sovereign-ai-innovations-with-center-of-excellence-for-applied-ai-with-nvidia/embed/#?secret=Iy11AniChG#?secret=6HFCmudlUc" data-secret="6HFCmudlUc" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanium appoints Satyen Desai as New Regional Vice President for ASEAN</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/tanium-appoints-satyen-desai-as-new-regional-vice-president-for-asean/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Tanium]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117354</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Tanium, a global autonomous endpoint management (AEM) firm, announced Wednesday the appointment of Satyen Desai, as its Regional Vice President (RVP), ASEAN. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-171850-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.tanium.com/">Tanium</a>, a global autonomous endpoint management (AEM) firm, announced Wednesday the appointment of Satyen Desai, as its Regional Vice President (RVP), ASEAN. </p>
<p>In this role, Desai will be responsible for accelerating Tanium’s growth in the region as demand grows for resilient, real-time endpoint management and security, Tanium said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Tanium also strengthened its leadership bench in  APAC, reinforcing the company’s commitment to serving regional customers with dedicated expertise across commercial execution, marketing, technical and customer outcomes. </p>
<p>These include Junya Saito, Vice President, Asia Pacific (APAC), Will oversee full commercial leadership for the APAC region, including revenue growth, sales, team development, and market expansion.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, James Greenwood, Assistant Vice President (AVP), Solution Engineering, will drive Solution Engineering (SE/Pre-Sales) across the region.</p>
<p>Yasir Yousuff, Vice President, Marketing, APJ, will head overall marketing strategy and execution across the Asia Pacific &amp; Japan (APJ) region.</p>
<p>The revamped leadership bench will deepen customer and partner engagement, and scale regional execution to help customers build a strong offensive security posture by delivering real-time, continuous visibility across their information technology (IT) environments.</p>
<p>“Autonomous endpoint management is becoming foundational for organizations that need to strengthen security and resilience, while operating at greater scale and speed,” said Satyen Desai, Regional Vice President, ASEAN, Tanium. </p>
<p>“Endpoints remain a primary entry point for threats across Asia, especially for governments and critical sectors. In this complex IT environment, customers need real-time visibility and control, plus the ability to autonomously recommend and execute changes with confidence, </p>
<p>&#8220;Tanium is purpose-built for this shift, and our leadership team will work closely with customers and partners to understand their pain points, reduce risk, and build certainty across their endpoint estates,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>An experienced enterprise technology leader, Desai brings over 25+ years of experience in enterprise technology, with a track record of building high-performing teams and delivering sustainable growth across ASEAN. </p>
<p>Prior to joining Tanium, he held leadership roles at ColorTokens, Cloudflare, Oracle , SAP and Cisco. </p>
<p>He helped scale go-to-market operations, expand strategic accounts, and strengthen partner ecosystems in the region. </p>
<p>It is noted that Tanium AEM empowers organizations to confidently scale operations and strengthen their security posture by autonomously recommending and executing changes across the environment. </p>
<p>Today’s IT operations and security teams face unprecedented pressure to reduce risk and secure every endpoint in real time, while accelerating operational efficiency. </p>
<p>With its unique real-time architecture, Tanium said it enables teams to act with speed, precision, and control, meeting the challenges of today’s dynamic threat landscape head-on. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CTsHLEwPIh"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/23/workday-appoints-tech-veteran-yen-yen-tan-to-apac-international-advisory-board/">Workday appoints tech veteran Yen Yen Tan to APAC International Advisory Board</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Workday appoints tech veteran Yen Yen Tan to APAC International Advisory Board&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/23/workday-appoints-tech-veteran-yen-yen-tan-to-apac-international-advisory-board/embed/#?secret=WxtJATPRVH#?secret=CTsHLEwPIh" data-secret="CTsHLEwPIh" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maybank sees Sea’s Monee well positioned to benefit from AI-driven payment</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/maybank-sees-seas-monee-well-positioned-to-benefit-from-ai-driven-payment/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 09:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117347</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Despite the artificial intelligence (AI)-related Shopee uncertainties, Maybank Investment Bank sees Monee well positioned to benefit from AI-driven payments while also capturing a portion of Shopee’s monetization upside.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/Screenshot-2024-03-05-131811-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>Despite the artificial intelligence (AI)-related Shopee uncertainties, Maybank Investment Bank sees <a href="https://www.sea.com/">Sea Ltd</a>&#8216;s Monee well positioned to benefit from AI-driven payments while also capturing a portion of Shopee’s monetization upside.</p>
<p>The research house said in a note on Tuesday that AI introduces new monetization vectors for Monee across defensible financial layers. </p>
<p>&#8220;As agentic transactions scale, licensed wallets remain central to authorization, settlement, fraud controls, and embedded credit/buy now pay later (BNPL), supporting ShopeePay/Monee’s role as a critical execution rail, </p>
<p>&#8220;Sea’s early collaboration with Google on AP2 highlights potential participation in emerging agentic payment flows. Beyond payments, AI lowers advisory and servicing costs, enabling scalable small-ticket wealth products, evidenced by MariBank’s more than $1 billion money market fund and USD1-entry gold-linked trust,&#8221; said the research house. </p>
<p>According to Maybank, AP2 standardizes how AI agents initiate transactions but still relies on licensed wallets and settlement rails.</p>
<p>ShopeePay, through Monee, already controls key components — stored value balances, KYC-linked identities, merchant acceptance, and embedded credit — positioning it as a natural execution layer within emerging agentic commerce architectures.</p>
<p>Strategically, it noted AP2 compatibility could strengthen ShopeePay’s role as a wallet of choice, particularly in ASEAN where credit card penetration remains low and wallet-native behavior dominates. </p>
<p>As AI interfaces increasingly influence discovery and checkout, it opined that globally scaled agents will require trusted local payment endpoints.</p>
<p>&#8220;ShopeePay’s integration into agentic payment flows may accelerate adoption beyond the Shopee ecosystem, consolidating consumer usage across a wider set of online and offline payment scenarios rather than remaining tethered solely to marketplace activity,&#8221; it added. </p>
<p>From defensive angle, Maybank highlighted the issue of protection against AI disintermediation. </p>
<p>According to the research house, this evolution is economically meaningful for Sea’s digital financial services strategy. </p>
<p>Even if AI agents compress marketplace monetization levers, it noted payments, credit authorization, and fraud management remain structurally defensible layers. </p>
<p>&#8220;Expanding ShopeePay’s relevance from transaction support to ecosystem-level infrastructure preserves value capture while creating new demand vectors, </p>
<p>&#8220;In this context, agentic payment standards such as AP2 could act as adoption catalysts, deepening ShopeePay’s utility, reinforcing network effects, and supporting monetization durability at the Monee level,&#8221; it said. </p>
<p>For Maybank, Sea’s Monee business presents structural expansion opportunities beyond core payments and credit, particularly in AI-assisted wealth and investment products. </p>
<p>Globally, it noted platforms such as PayPal and Alipay have demonstrated that scaled payment ecosystems can successfully layer on investment and treasury products, including money market funds and low-ticket savings vehicles. </p>
<p>Wealthfront, Robinhood, and Nubank similarly illustrate how technology-led models enable small-balance investing by structurally lowering distribution and servicing costs, according to the research house. </p>
<p>&#8220;Monee to an extent has demonstrated this — 1) Monee operates the 4th largest money market fund in Singapore, which has surpassed $1 billion in asset under management (AUM) and 2) Monee recently launched Singapore’s first physical gold-linked unit trust. Users can invest starting with $1 in these funds/trusts,</p>
<p>&#8220;AI capabilities further accelerate this transition by compressing advisory and customer acquisition frictions,&#8221; said Maybank. </p>
<p>It also said that automated portfolio construction, risk profiling, and conversational interfaces materially reduce the cost-to-serve for mass-market users — a dynamic visible across digital wealth platforms and neobanks. </p>
<p>&#8220;This shift is particularly relevant for emerging markets, where traditional wealth management models remain inaccessible due to<br />
high minimum balances and limited financial advisory penetration, it added. </p>
<p>It is noted that AI commerce has rapidly progressed from early plugin-based models focused on assisted discovery all the way to native in-chat checkout (WalmartOpenAI). OpenAI (ACP) &amp; Google (UCP) are advancing open protocols to standardize agent-led transactions. </p>
<p>Adoption signals are encouraging: Adobe reported a 47 times year on year surge in generative AI-driven retail traffic, Salesforce estimated AI influenced about 20 percent of global holiday sales, while Similarweb observed ChatGPT drove 15 percent of Walmart referral traffic in Sep-2025. </p>
<p>&#8220;As AI interfaces move closer to checkout, they increasingly influence discovery, advertising, payments, data control &amp; broader platform monetization layers,&#8221; said Maybank. </p>
<p>The research house also evaluated three scenarios for Shopee, ranging from a bear case where it risks becoming merely a logistics utility to a positive outcome where AI acts as a<br />
gross merchandise value (GMV) capture funnel while Shopee retains its platform moats, by varying unit economics &amp; GMV. </p>
<p>The scenarios differ across key AI-driven levers, including AI-sourced GMV share, agent channel fees, ad revenue migration, take-rates, corporate affairs commission (CAC) relief, and incremental technology costs. </p>
<p>&#8220;Based on differing value leakage or accretion assumptions across monetization layers, we estimate Shopee’s long-term margin outcomes could range between 0.6 percent and 2.8 percent, versus our base case of 2.5 percent,&#8221; said Maybank. </p>
<p>Incorporating potential GMV impacts under agentic commerce pathways, it sees Sea’s valuation exposure spanning a material downside of -54 percent to upside of +21 percent, highlighting asymmetric risk reward dynamics as AI interfaces increasingly influence platform economics.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NBjVBbIphP"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/19/sea-and-google-deepen-partnership-to-deliver-ai-powered-innovations-for-consumers-globally/">Sea and Google deepen partnership to deliver AI-powered innovations for consumers globally</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Sea and Google deepen partnership to deliver AI-powered innovations for consumers globally&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/19/sea-and-google-deepen-partnership-to-deliver-ai-powered-innovations-for-consumers-globally/embed/#?secret=uogm4LJcrx#?secret=NBjVBbIphP" data-secret="NBjVBbIphP" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFC commits $25M to Seraya Partners Fund II to support sustainable infrastructure development in Southeast Asia</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/ifc-commits-25m-to-seraya-partners-fund-ii-to-support-sustainable-infrastructure-development-in-southeast-asia/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[IFC]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Seraya Partners]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117345</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-350x350.jpeg 350w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-348x348.jpeg 348w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC.jpeg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />The International Finance Corporation (IFC), a member of the World Bank Group and the largest global development institution focused on the private sector in emerging markets, has committed $25 million to Seraya Partners Fund I, a private equity infrastructure fund managed by Seraya Partners, to support sustainable infrastructure development in Southeast Asia.
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-350x350.jpeg 350w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC-348x348.jpeg 348w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/IFC.jpeg 750w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>The <a href="https://www.ifc.org/en/home">International Finance Corporation (IFC)</a>, a member of the World Bank Group and the largest global development institution focused on the private sector in emerging markets, has committed $25 million to Seraya Partners Fund I, a private equity infrastructure fund managed by Seraya Partners, to support sustainable infrastructure development in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>IFC said in a statement on Wednesday that the move is to address critical infrastructure gaps in emerging markets in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>IFC’s $25 million equity commitment anchors the fund’s Southeast Asia Emerging Markets sleeve, which targets investments that support decarbonization, improved connectivity, and inclusive economic growth, with a core focus on Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Thailand, and Vietnam. </p>
<p>Development impact will be monitored through indicators including renewable energy generation and digital capacity expansion.</p>
<p>This is Seraya’s first dedicated sleeve to invest in emerging markets in Southeast Asia. </p>
<p>It will invest alongside the Fund’s other sleeve, which is dedicated to developed markets in Asia Pacific. </p>
<p>Together, investments in both sleeves are intended to connect the value chain across developed and developing markets, fostering greater regional integration and new economic opportunities, including job creation.</p>
<p>“IFC’s investment in Seraya Partners Fund II is aimed at improving access to quality infrastructure in emerging markets in Southeast Asia,</p>
<p>“Our investment also aims to signal confidence in investing in critical infrastructure projects in these markets and help channel more private capital into the region, which will ultimately support long-term economic resilience in Southeast Asia,&#8221; said Katherine Koh, Regional Industry Manager for Infrastructure and Natural Resources, Asia Pacific at IFC. </p>
<p>James Chern, Managing Partner and Chief Investment Officer of Seraya Partners, said Seraya Partners is honored to partner with IFC on the fund. </p>
<p>&#8220;IFC’s commitment validates our differentiated strategy to invest in infrastructure that supports Asia’s emerging markets, </p>
<p>&#8220;This strategic partnership will help deliver measurable impact across the region,&#8221; he added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eHcBrajmsG"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/17/smfg-ifc-partner-to-launch-the-worlds-first-digital-inclusion-bond-supporting-msmes-in-emerging-markets/">SMFG, IFC partner to launch $500M digital inclusion bond, supporting MSMEs in emerging markets</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;SMFG, IFC partner to launch $500M digital inclusion bond, supporting MSMEs in emerging markets&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/17/smfg-ifc-partner-to-launch-the-worlds-first-digital-inclusion-bond-supporting-msmes-in-emerging-markets/embed/#?secret=owRONFPd8I#?secret=eHcBrajmsG" data-secret="eHcBrajmsG" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vinfast Middle East inks deal with PlusX Electric to strengthen EV ownership experience in the UAE</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/25/vinfast-middle-east-inks-deal-with-plusx-electric-to-strengthen-ev-ownership-experience-in-the-uae/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Electric Vehicles & Mobility]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[VinFast]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117337</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Vietnam-based electric vehicles (EVs) maker VinFast announced Monday the signing of a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with PlusX Electric, a DEWA-approved EV charging and electric mobility solutions provider in the United Arab Emirates (UAE). 
]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-25-154335-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>Vietnam-based electric vehicles (EVs) maker<a href="https://me.vinfast.com/en"> VinFast </a>announced Monday the signing of a memorandum of understanding (MoU) with PlusX Electric, a DEWA-approved EV charging and electric mobility solutions provider in the United Arab Emirates (UAE). </p>
<p>The collaboration aims to enhance charging accessibility and strengthen customer support services, reinforcing the overall EV ownership experience for VinFast customers in the UAE, VinFast said in a statement. </p>
<p>The partnership is designed to provide greater confidence throughout the EV ownership journey—ensuring that premium electric vehicles are supported by reliable charging solutions, responsive roadside assistance, and integrated digital services. </p>
<p>By combining VinFast&#8217;s expanding EV presence in the UAE with PlusX Electric&#8217;s on-demand charging capabilities and infrastructure expertise, the two parties will work together to deliver a seamless, convenience-led, and assurance-driven experience for VinFast drivers.</p>
<p>Under the MoU, VinFast and PlusX Electric will collaborate across a structured set of initiatives focused on charging availability, ownership support, and infrastructure enablement across key use cases, including home, workplace, fleet, and on-road assistance.</p>
<p>Specifically, the two parties aim to deploy Portable EV Charging Pods to meet customers&#8217; flexible charging needs during vehicle usage, while enabling access to on-demand mobile charging services designed to assist in time-sensitive situations. </p>
<p>The partnership will also explore EV roadside assistance (RSA) – emergency charging services, helping reduce range anxiety and vehicle downtime while strengthening customer assurance through clearly defined service workflows and operational readiness.</p>
<p>In addition, PlusX Electric may become a preferred partner for the supply, installation, and aftersales support of Home &amp; Office Chargers for VinFast customers in the UAE, in alignment with applicable UAE compliance requirements. </p>
<p>For commercial and fleet segments, the two parties will explore scalable solutions such as DC fast charger leasing and dedicated mobile charging support, ensuring operational continuity and efficiency for business to business (B2B) and fleet customers.</p>
<p>As part of the collaboration, VinFast and PlusX Electric will further explore digital integration initiatives to streamline how customers access charging services, manage bookings, and receive service updates through partner platforms. </p>
<p>The two parties will also assess potential integration of EV insurance offerings via the PlusX App and explore co-branding opportunities, including VinFast branding on PlusX Power Pods, with the objective of delivering a cohesive and fully integrated EV ecosystem experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;VinFast is committed to building a long-term and comprehensive EV ecosystem in the UAE—one that gives customers confidence not only in the quality and performance of our electric vehicles, but also in the reliability and accessibility of the supporting infrastructure, </p>
<p>&#8220;Through this MoU with PlusX Electric, we are strengthening the support layer around EV adoption by expanding access to flexible charging solutions, emergency assistance services, and integrated digital touchpoints,&#8221; said Do Hoai Linh, Chief Executive Officer of VinFast Middle East.</p>
<p>&#8220;By working with a DEWA-approved partner that understands local regulatory requirements and operational realities, we aim to make EV ownership simpler, more dependable, and better aligned with the expectations of customers in the Middle East,&#8221; she added. </p>
<p>Chintan Sareen, Founder and Chief Executive Officer of PlusX Electric, added that EV adoption accelerates when customers trust that charging and support are always within reach. </p>
<p>&#8220;Our collaboration with VinFast reflects a shared commitment to strengthening the EV ownership ecosystem in the UAE through dependable infrastructure, responsive roadside services, and customer-centric digital solutions, </p>
<p>&#8220;As a DEWA-approved provider, PlusX Electric brings localized expertise in charger supply and installation, mobile charging operations, and fleet enablement. Together with VinFast, we look forward to delivering practical, scalable solutions that enhance service reliability, reduce range anxiety, and support the continued growth of sustainable mobility in the region,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>Across the Middle East, VinFast said continues to expand its presence through strategic partnerships, strengthened aftersales capabilities, and the development of EV-supporting infrastructure.</p>
<p>The collaboration with PlusX Electric underscores VinFast&#8217;s long-term commitment to supporting customers throughout their ownership journey and contributing to the UAE&#8217;s transition toward sustainable and future-ready mobility solutions.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="elbeD4KNEj"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/11/vinfast-partners-exposure-sarl-to-promote-green-transportation-in-the-democratic-republic-of-congo/">VinFast partners Exposure SARL to promote green transportation in the Democratic Republic of Congo</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;VinFast partners Exposure SARL to promote green transportation in the Democratic Republic of Congo&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/11/vinfast-partners-exposure-sarl-to-promote-green-transportation-in-the-democratic-republic-of-congo/embed/#?secret=9E6c6xcMxQ#?secret=elbeD4KNEj" data-secret="elbeD4KNEj" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
