<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
    <atom:link href="https://technode.global/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
    <description>Latest news and trends about tech</description>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:52:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9.1</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/cropped-technode-icon-2020_512x512-32x32.png</url>
      <title>News Archive - TNGlobal</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/category/news/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>The Invention Lab completes seed investment in Singapore’s AI computing startup RIDM</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/the-invention-lab-completes-seed-investment-in-singapores-ai-computing-startup-ridm/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[RIDM]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117533</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />The South Korea-based venture capital firm The Invention Lab has completed its seed investment in a Singapore-based artificial intelligence (AI) computing startup RIDM.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-214436-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>The South Korea-based venture capital firm The Invention Lab has completed its seed investment in a Singapore-based artificial intelligence (AI) computing startup RIDM.</p>
<p>The Invention Lab said in a statement on Friday that this investment was made jointly with London-based global quant investment firm Qube Research &amp; Technologies (QRT).</p>
<p>According to the statement, the joint investment is betting on a unique architecture to solve memory bottlenecks founded by a team of engineers from National University of Singapore (NUS), actively pursuing commercialization based on three international patents.</p>
<p>RIDM is a deep tech startup that has developed a unique computing architecture called &#8216;DODA (Dynamically Orchestrated Dataflow Architecture)&#8217; to solve the &#8216;Memory Wall&#8217; problem, which is considered a core technical challenge in AI and high-performance computing (HPC) environments. </p>
<p>RIDM has successfully simplified the &#8216;spatial compilation&#8217; problem, which has been regarded as a difficult problem for decades, in linear time, and is evaluated to provide a competitive development environment compared to the existing CUDA ecosystem through development in a general-purpose programming language (C++).</p>
<p>Currently, RIDM is conducting a proof of concept (PoC) in collaboration with QRT. Both companies are focusing on FPGA development and acceleration utilizing RIDM&#8217;s DODA architecture, which is a core use case that requires extreme efficiency and low latency.</p>
<p>The founder and Chief Executive Officer Jin-ho Lee, pursued a Ph.D. on general-purpose dataflow architecture at the NUS, and this research has been registered as a patent held by NUS. </p>
<p>RIDM has secured a foundation for commercialization by receiving this patent under an exclusive license. </p>
<p>Technical advisor Trevor E. Carlson, an associate professor in the Department of Computer Science at NUS, is the main developer of the multi-core simulator SniperSim and was involved in designing the technical basis of RIDM.</p>
<p>&#8220;RIDM is a next-generation technology team that is directly breaking through the limitations of traditional computing structures, </p>
<p>&#8220;It is a bet on the technology itself, but also an expression of trust in the execution capabilities of the team that is realizing it and their balanced business judgment,&#8221; said Jin-young Kim, Chief Executive Officer of The Invention Lab.</p>
<p>RIDM currently maintains a lightweight structure centered on IP based on three international patents and plans to seek strategic collaborations with global companies based on the results of technology verification, said the statement. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6i8AlOIs4J"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/27/tbwasingapore-establishes-first-apac-innovation-center-of-excellence-to-scale-ai-led-brand-innovation/">TBWASingapore establishes first APAC innovation Center of Excellence to scale AI-led brand Innovation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;TBWASingapore establishes first APAC innovation Center of Excellence to scale AI-led brand Innovation&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/27/tbwasingapore-establishes-first-apac-innovation-center-of-excellence-to-scale-ai-led-brand-innovation/embed/#?secret=KV73JwULdN#?secret=6i8AlOIs4J" data-secret="6i8AlOIs4J" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASEAN endorses Malaysia-led regional framework on cross border cloud computing</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/asean-endorses-malaysia-led-regional-framework-on-cross-border-cloud-computing/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 13:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Digital Transformation]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[SEA]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[MDEC]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117528</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has endorsed a Regional Framework on Cross-Border Cloud Computing conceived, developed and spearheaded by the Ministry of Digital through its agency, the Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation (MDEC), marking a strategic milestone aimed at enabling trusted and seamless data flows across member states while supporting regional digital integration and growth. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-212238-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has endorsed a Regional Framework on Cross-Border Cloud Computing conceived, developed and spearheaded by the Ministry of Digital through its agency, the Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation (MDEC), marking a strategic milestone aimed at enabling trusted and seamless data flows across member states while supporting regional digital integration and growth. </p>
<p>MDEC said in a statement on Thursday that the framework was endorsed at the 6th ASEAN Digital Ministers’ Meeting (ADGMIN) held recently in Hanoi, Vietnam. It sets out common principles for legal and regulatory governance of cloud computing to support cross-border data hosting while strengthening safeguards for data protection among ASEAN member states. </p>
<p>Malaysia&#8217;s Minister of Digital Gobind Singh Deo said that the framework is designed to provide greater regulatory clarity, raise data governance standards and support secure and seamless cross-border data flows as the region’s digital economy expands and continues to thrive. </p>
<p>“This regional framework balances data protection, legal certainty and business innovation. It strengthens investor confidence across jurisdictions while supporting the growth of cross-border digital trade and digital services,” he said. </p>
<p>The framework introduces shared principles for cloud data governance, including safeguards for data at rest and in transit, clearer rules on regulatory access, alignment with international standards and introduces the concept of Trusted Data Corridors (TDC) to facilitate secure cross-border data hosting and transfers. </p>
<p>It also provides guidance for regulated sectors such as healthcare and financial services in adopting cloud technologies without compromising regulatory requirements, data protection or operational resilience. </p>
<p>“The framework is also timely as Malaysia’s data center and cloud ecosystem continues to expand, reinforcing our nation’s position as a regional hub for cloud computing and artificial intelligence (AI) while further strengthening international investor and industry confidence,” added Gobind. </p>
<p>MDEC Chief Executive Officer, Anuar Fariz Fadzil described the framework as reflecting strong regional cooperation to reduce regulatory friction and unlock new investment and innovation opportunities across all ASEAN member states. </p>
<p>“Regulatory fragmentation has long been a challenge for businesses operating across ASEAN, </p>
<p>&#8220;This framework offers a practical approach to harmonizing rules, reducing compliance risks and supporting the growth of cloud-enabled and data-driven services,” he said. </p>
<p>Anuar added that the framework also supports Malaysia’s broader digital economy strategy to attract high-quality investments, strengthen the cloud and data center ecosystem and enable both local and regional companies to scale considerably using trusted digital infrastructure in line with the AI Nation 2030 objectives. </p>
<p>“As cloud and digital technologies become more central to economic growth and shared regional prosperity, ASEAN needs clear and interoperable frameworks to support seamless cross-border digital activity, </p>
<p>&#8220;This framework is an important step towards building a trusted regional digital foundation and could also serve as a model for other regions globally,” added Anuar. </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Asian Business Law Institute (ABLI), which acted as consultant to the project, said the framework serves as “a comprehensive policy instrument combining high-level principles with practical guidance”, and is intended to support trusted and seamless cross-border cloud adoption region-wide. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="nRT4gmqWJf"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/17/futurise-moves-to-mdec-for-greater-alignment-to-strengthen-malaysias-digital-future-economy-agenda/">Futurise moves to MDEC for greater alignment to strengthen Malaysia’s digital &amp; future economy agenda</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Futurise moves to MDEC for greater alignment to strengthen Malaysia’s digital &amp; future economy agenda&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/17/futurise-moves-to-mdec-for-greater-alignment-to-strengthen-malaysias-digital-future-economy-agenda/embed/#?secret=E9csqsKv8y#?secret=nRT4gmqWJf" data-secret="nRT4gmqWJf" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASPAC region sees both fintech deal value and volume fall to ten-year lows – KPMG</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/aspac-region-sees-both-fintech-deal-value-and-volume-fall-to-ten-year-lows-kpmg/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 09:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117516</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Asia Pacific (ASPAC)'s fintech deal value and deal volume dropped from an already soft $11.7 billion across 1,028 in 2024 to $9.3 billion across 763 deals in 2025 — levels not seen in over ten years, KPMG said in its recent report. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-172250-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>Asia Pacific (ASPAC)&#8217;s fintech deal value and deal volume dropped from an already soft $11.7 billion across 1,028 in 2024 to $9.3 billion across 763 deals in 2025 — levels not seen in over ten years, <a href="https://kpmg.com/xx/en.html">KPMG</a> said in its recent report. </p>
<p>According to the report, the drop was driven by a number of factors, including geopolitical tensions, macroeconomic factors, and continued caution on the part of fintech investors. </p>
<p>Total fintech investment was relatively steady between the first and second half of the year — with $4.8 billion across 401 deals and $4.6 billion across 362 deals respectively.</p>
<p>While deal sizes were relatively soft compared to historical norms, a range of jurisdictions attracted $100 million+ deals during the second half of 2025, including Australia-founded, now Singapore-based, Airwallex — which raised a $330 million venture capital (VC) round, the purchase of majority stake in Japan-based artificial intelligence (AI)-driven business credit solutions firm Upsider by Mizuho Financial Group for $313.6 million, a $200 million VC raise by South Korea-based fintech super app Toss, and a $140 million VC raise by Indonesia-based credit card issuer Honest.</p>
<p>According to the report, VC investment accounted for the lion’s share of fintech investment in the ASPAC region during 2025, accounting for $7.5 billion across 672 deals, while merger and acquisition (M&amp;A) activity accounted for $1.7 billion across 82 deals, and private equity (PE) activity accounted for just $101.8 million across nine deals.</p>
<p>A number of jurisdictions in the ASPAC region saw a slowdown in investment between 2024 and 2025. </p>
<p>In China, total investment fell from $991.7 million to $876.1 million year-over-year — driven by a combination of persistent economic challenges, geopolitical tensions, and increasingly tight regulations. </p>
<p>In Australia, fintech investment fell from $1.9 billion to $609 million as the market continued to experience some rightsizing. </p>
<p>South Korea — a relatively nascent fintech hub in the region — was one exception to the fintech investment downturn in 2025; it saw fintech investment rise from $245.6 million to $402.4 million year-over-year — although half of this investment came from Toss’s $200 million VC raise.</p>
<p>&#8220;Across the fintech landscape we’re seeing some of the smaller providers looking at consolidation to drive scale and maintain relevance, as well as broaden capability among firms targeting slightly different parts of the market and customer cohorts, </p>
<p>&#8220;These kinds of consolidation deals almost always make sense because they create more longevity, profitability and sustainability,&#8221; said Daniel Teper Partner, M&amp;A and Head of Fintech KPMG Australia.</p>
<p>The report also highlighted that AI continuing to be a key focus for investors across the ASPAC region &#8211; including large language models (LLMs), generative AI applications and agentic AI &#8211; with increasing focus on real world solutions in the first half of 2026.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there is a growing focus on turning data into variable and tradable assets, in combination with an increasing focus on privacy computing. </p>
<p>The report also showed China-based fintechs are embracing dual-market routes to grow overseas &#8211; replicating domestic payments and microcredit models in emerging markets, while focusing on more transformative solutions in mature markets. </p>
<p>Macroeconomic and geopolitical uncertainties continuing to drive caution among fintech investors, including the protracted economic slowdown in China and increasing concern that inflationary pressures in Australia could lead to a rate increase, according to KPMG. </p>
<p>It noted that financial institutions in Australia which are prioritizing fintechs are able to help them drive efficiencies and cost reductions.</p>
<p>It also highlighted growth of digital asset capability, incubation and scaling programs across Japan, Korea, Singapore and Australia. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="yZ7vWbskqz"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/09/26/kpmg-singapores-fintech-investment-rebounds-to-1-04b-in-first-half/">KPMG: Singapore’s fintech investment rebounds to $1.04B in first half</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;KPMG: Singapore’s fintech investment rebounds to $1.04B in first half&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/09/26/kpmg-singapores-fintech-investment-rebounds-to-1-04b-in-first-half/embed/#?secret=GcYxj1Mge9#?secret=yZ7vWbskqz" data-secret="yZ7vWbskqz" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia’s Catcha Digital achieves record full-year revenue and profit</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/malaysias-catcha-digital-achieves-record-full-year-revenue-and-profit/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Media / Streaming]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Catcha Digital]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117513</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-165920-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" />Malaysia-based Catcha Digital Berhad has achieved record full-year revenue and profit during the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025).]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-165920-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" /><p>Malaysia-based<a href="https://www.catchadigital.com/"> Catcha Digital Berhad </a>has achieved record full-year revenue and profit during the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025).</p>
<p>The firm said in a statement on Thursday that its posted a revenue of MYR 67.63 million ($17.39 million) during the year, surging 76 percent year on year. </p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s adjusted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA) stood at MYR 14.76 million ($3.79 million), soaring 83 percent year on year. </p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s adjusted profit after tax and minority interests (PATAMI) also jumped 64 percent year on year to MYR 8.54 million ($2.2 million).</p>
<p>“Our team has delivered an exceptional year of growth. This performance is a direct result of the successful integration of our recent acquisitions in the B2B expo space and the continued expansion of our digital media business,” said Eric Tan, Chief Executive Officer of Catcha Digital Berhad. </p>
<p>“While our reported statutory figures include significant non-cash accounting adjustments related to our M&amp;A activities, our underlying operating performance and cash flow remain very strong,</p>
<p>&#8220;We are focused on unlocking the full earnings potential of our new acquisitions and maintaining a sustainable growth trajectory for our shareholders,&#8221; he added. </p>
<p>The group’s growth in 2025 was bolstered by the contribution of newly acquired entities, including One International Exhibition Sdn Bhd, which contributed MYR 7.17 million ($1.84 million) in revenue. </p>
<p>In December 2025 alone, the group completed the acquisitions of Maxoom Sdn Bhd and Framemotion Studio Sdn Bhd, and increased its stake in Headline Media Sdn Bhd from 30 percent to 80 percent.</p>
<p>This acquisition-led expansion is supported by a solid capital base. </p>
<p>In late 2025, the Group successfully completed a MYR 24.3 million ($6.25 million) rights issue of shares with warrants, which was 78 percent oversubscribed. </p>
<p>The group said when these warrants are fully exercised, it is poised to potentially raise up to an additional MYR 73 million ($18.77 million) to fuel its growth plans. </p>
<p>This capital, combined with the MYR 35 million ($9 million) revolving credit facility finalized with Affin Hwang Investment Bank Berhad on August 28, 2025, and robust operating cash flow of RM11m generated in FY2025, positions the group well for continued growth. </p>
<p>As of December 31, 2025, the group maintains a strong cash position of MYR 30.74 million ($7.9 million).</p>
<p>With total available acquisition capital of well over MYR 100 million ($25.71 million), the group said it is exceptionally well-positioned to continue executing on its strategy of high-impact, earnings-accretive acquisitions. </p>
<p>“Looking ahead to FY2026, the group expects full-year financial contributions from seven acquisitions in 2025, </p>
<p>&#8220;We will continue to evaluate a robust pipeline of acquisition opportunities across our core pillars of digital media, B2B expo, and information technology (IT) solutions as we continue to build the permanent home for market-leading companies in these pillars,&#8221; said Patrick Grove, Chairman of Catcha Digital.</p>
<p>Catcha Digital said it has completed 7 acquisitions in 2025, each positioned to strengthen its foothold in the digital media, B2B expo and technology space, all expected to contribute positively to future earnings. </p>
<p>The aggregate expected profit to be achieved by each target company as disclosed below is approximately MYR 16.1 million ($4.14 million) on a proforma basis, based on their respective 12-month post-completion periods or FY2025 where applicable.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="VvJMAAeprg"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/12/23/catcha-increases-stake-in-headline-media-to-80-percent/">Catcha increases stake in Headline Media to 80 percent</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Catcha increases stake in Headline Media to 80 percent&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/12/23/catcha-increases-stake-in-headline-media-to-80-percent/embed/#?secret=I9MGithbyn#?secret=VvJMAAeprg" data-secret="VvJMAAeprg" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TBWA\Singapore establishes first APAC innovation Center of Excellence to scale AI-led brand Innovation</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/tbwasingapore-establishes-first-apac-innovation-center-of-excellence-to-scale-ai-led-brand-innovation/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[TBWA\Singapore]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117508</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />TBWA\Singapore announced Wednesday the launch of its Innovation Lab, the first Center of Excellence in TBWA’s Asia-Pacific network established with support from the Singapore Economic Development Board (EDB). ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/TBWAxEDB-Innovation-Lab-Press-Image-1-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.tbwa.com.sg/">TBWA\Singapore </a>announced Wednesday the launch of its Innovation Lab, the first Center of Excellence in TBWA’s Asia-Pacific network established with support from the Singapore Economic Development Board (EDB). </p>
<p>The firm said in a statement that the lab establishes Singapore as a regional proving ground for AI-led brand innovation, helping companies translate ambition into scalable experiences, intelligent systems, and new growth models enabled by emerging technologies.</p>
<p>According to the statement, the lab has been established in response to a fundamental shift facing brands. </p>
<p>It is noted that as customer expectations evolve faster than traditional marketing and innovation cycles, ambition alone is no longer enough. Brands need to be able to build, test, and learn at speed, while ensuring ideas are credible, scalable, and commercially sound.</p>
<p>“Technology has finally caught up with creative ambition. AI and immersive platforms allow us to build, test, and learn at a pace the industry simply couldn’t achieve before, </p>
<p>&#8220;This lab exists to ensure that speed is used responsibly, creating brand experiences that are richer, more engaging, and grounded in real value, not hype,&#8221; said Mandy Wong, Chief Executive Officer, TBWA\Group Singapore. </p>
<p>Unlike traditional innovation labs that often rely on large-scale, long-horizon, and high-cost initiatives that take months to prove and are difficult to unwind once committed, TBWA\Singapore said its lab is built to deliver outcomes through rapid prototyping, early proof, and disciplined scale. </p>
<p>Its role is to help brands identify new growth spaces, rapidly test ideas, and scale only what earns the right to grow.</p>
<p>The firm highlighted that artificial intelligence sits at the core of the lab’s model, collapsing timelines across insight, ideation, experience design, and production. </p>
<p>This allows teams to prototype immersive brand experiences in weeks rather than months, pressure-test ideas early, and compound learning rather than resetting with each new project.</p>
<p>The lab also focuses on how emerging technologies unlock opportunities that were previously impractical or out of reach. Robotics and intelligent systems are applied to solve complex human and business challenges across education, training, service<br />
design, and social impact. </p>
<p>Virtual and augmented reality are used to extend brands into new realms, creating environments audiences can step into, interact with, and return to, rather than passively consume.</p>
<p>“We’re interested in the spaces where creativity and systems collide. AI, robotics, and spatial computing let us prototype experiences and operating models that used to be too slow, too complex, or too risky to attempt, </p>
<p>&#8220;Our job is to make those ideas real, usable, and scalable,&#8221; said Mel Daniels, Head of Innovation, TBWA\Asia and TBWA\Singapore.</p>
<p>According to the statement, the launch of the lab formalizes capabilities TBWA\Singapore has already proven in market, including immersive experience platforms developed for Singapore’s arts and culture industry to deepen audience engagement through interactive digital environments. </p>
<p>The lab also extends existing work in designing bespoke AI agents and AI-enabled operating systems integrated into real creative, production, and strategic workflows.</p>
<p>Supported by the Singapore Economic Development Board (EDB), the Innovation Lab will develop, test and refine ideas and experiences, before scaling them across clients, categories and global markets. </p>
<p>At the same time, partnerships with educational institutions and other industry players will uplift the local tech and innovation ecosystem.</p>
<p>“TBWA\Singapore&#039;s Innovation Lab will harness AI in marketing and advertising to support businesses, while partnering our Institutes of Higher Learning to develop the next generation of AI-savvy talent, </p>
<p>&#8220;Firms like TBWA\Singapore play an important role in Singapore&#8217;s marketing ecosystem, strengthening our position as a trusted hub for professional services. We look forward to working with TBWA\Singapore to advance AI transformation in the marketing sector,&#8221; said Junie Fo, Vice President and Head of Professional Services, EDB.</p>
<p>Beyond client delivery, the lab also plays a central role in shaping the agency’s future talent strategy. </p>
<p>Under the leadership of Mandy Goh, Head of Talent and Human Resources of TBWA\Singapore, the lab will operate as a training and incubation platform for the hybrid skillsets the industry will require over the next 12 to 18 months, blending creativity, technology, systems thinking, and cultural intelligence.</p>
<p>“The future of our industry depends on new hybrid skillsets. The Innovation Lab gives us a live environment to train, experiment, and incubate talent for the roles the agency and our clients will need next, not just the ones that exist today,&#8221; said Goh. </p>
<p>This includes upskilling existing talent, developing new career pathways, and incubating roles that do not yet formally exist, ensuring both the agency and its clients are prepared for what’s next rather than reacting to it.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="eIs13DKCRs"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/">Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Digital Realty expands innovation lab network to Singapore, Japan and London to accelerate AI and hybrid cloud implementation&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/digital-realty-expands-innovation-lab-network-to-singapore-japan-and-london-to-accelerate-ai-and-hybrid-cloud-implementation/embed/#?secret=hRytSH2DDh#?secret=eIs13DKCRs" data-secret="eIs13DKCRs" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Singapore organizations using AI, but reworking outputs dampens productivity – Workday</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/more-singapore-organizations-using-ai-but-reworking-outputs-dampens-productivity-workday/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Workday]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117504</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-162241-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" />Workday, Inc., the global enterprise artificial intelligence (AI) platform has released new research on Thursday that found the need to rework AI outputs is eroding productivity gains for employees. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-162241-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" /><p><a href="https://www.workday.com/">Workday, Inc.</a>, the global enterprise artificial intelligence (AI) platform has released new research on Thursday that found the need to rework AI outputs is eroding productivity gains for employees. </p>
<p>This signals a productivity gap that Singapore organizations will need to address, especially as AI use is becoming more widespread, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>The study, which surveyed 3,200 respondents globally, including in Singapore, found that approximately half of Singapore respondents spend at least an hour each week clarifying, correcting or even rewriting AI-generated outputs, with 12 percent spending between two to four hours weekly on rework alone.</p>
<p>Despite this, net productivity gains remain positive, with seven in ten respondents noting they are more productive today compared to pre-AI adoption levels. </p>
<p>All respondents indicated that AI tools are already deployed in their organizations, and 86 percent reported implementing three or more AI use cases.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, organizations in the region are broadly aligned that AI-driven efficiency gains should benefit employees. </p>
<p>Some 68 percent of respondents agree that companies that reinvest in their people will be more competitive and resilient over the long term.</p>
<p>Among respondents whose organizations reported time savings from AI adoption, 78 percent said those gains were reinvested in employee development, upskilling or training, while 68 percent redirected time towards higher-value, strategic or innovative work.</p>
<p>Notably, 80 percent said AI cost savings were reinvested in the workforce – matching the proportion reinvested in technology or infrastructure, and significantly exceeding the share returned to shareholders (23 percent).</p>
<p>“Reinvesting AI-driven gains into people is critical to improving outcomes and sustaining long-term value creation,” said Jess O’Reilly, general manager, ASEAN, Workday. </p>
<p>“AI can improve efficiency, but speed alone does not unlock real value. What makes the biggest difference is reinvesting those<br />
gains into people, </p>
<p>&#8220;Organizations will need to prioritize talent development in the core areas of AI literacy and critical thinking. Building confidence for employees in their use of AI will be pivotal to<br />
reducing rework, enhancing business outcomes and delivering lasting value,&#8221; she added. </p>
<p>As AI becomes embedded in daily workflows, employees reported growing performance expectations, said the study. </p>
<p>Six in ten respondents say they are now expected to deliver a significantly higher volume of output compared to before AI adoption.</p>
<p>Findings from the report show that the burden of rework largely sits at mid-managerial levels.</p>
<p>Managers and directors are most likely to shoulder the responsibility of validating, refining, and approving work, including AI-assisted output – reflecting their role as quality gatekeepers.</p>
<p>Despite heightened expectations, overall sentiment remains largely positive. </p>
<p>Most respondents (75 percent) say they trust their leadership teams to make fair decisions about AI’s impact on job security and<br />
rewards, while only 7 percent express concern about potential redundancy due to AI.</p>
<p>Six in 10 respondents also noted that their stress levels and risk of burnout have decreased since the deployment and adoption of AI tools.</p>
<p>The organizations realizing the greatest value from AI treat saved time as a strategic resource. </p>
<p>They reinvest in upskilling their teams, improving collaboration, and strengthening judgment-driven work.</p>
<p>The biggest opportunity is helping employees learn how to use AI effectively – especially in areas that require judgement, creativity, and decision-making. The research makes one thing clear: reinvesting in people is the fastest way to reduce rework, improve outcomes, and turn AI speed into lasting business value, said the statement. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="NfEeZOmU5M"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ais-impact-is-bigger-than-we-think/">AI&#8217;s impact is bigger than we think</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;AI&#8217;s impact is bigger than we think&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/26/ais-impact-is-bigger-than-we-think/embed/#?secret=pXGAshxExV#?secret=NfEeZOmU5M" data-secret="NfEeZOmU5M" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China’s XTransfer receives Malaysia Central Bank’s conditional approval for key payment licences</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/chinas-xtransfer-receives-malaysia-central-banks-conditional-approval-for-key-payment-licences/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[FinTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[XTransfer]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117501</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />XTransfer, the China-based business to business (B2B) cross-border trade payment platform, announced Wednesday that it has received conditional approval from Bank Negara Malaysia (BNM) for key payment licenses, including issuing electronic money, as well as a Money Services Business License (Class A) covering remittance and currency exchange.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-160804-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p>XTransfer, the China-based business to business (B2B) cross-border trade payment platform, announced Wednesday that it has received conditional approval from Bank Negara Malaysia (BNM) for key payment licenses, including issuing electronic money, as well as a Money Services Business License (Class A) covering remittance and currency exchange.</p>
<p>The firm said in a statement that upon completing the pre-issuance conditions and being permitted to launch, it plans to introduce digital payment services in Malaysia designed to support businesses, particularly small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) engaged in international trade. </p>
<p>These services are intended to include streamlined onboarding, convenient funding options, efficient foreign exchange, and secure remittance and settlement experiences, with a focus on compliance, security, and operational reliability, helping Malaysian SMEs reduce friction in legitimate trade as they scale into regional and emerging-market corridors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Receiving conditional approval from Bank Negara Malaysia is an important milestone for XTransfer in the ASEAN region,</p>
<p>&#8220;We appreciate BNM&#8217;s guidance and oversight. We look forward to bringing Malaysian businesses compliant and efficient payment solutions that help trade move faster and more predictably, especially as intra-Asia and broader South–South trade routes continue to expand,&#8221; said Bill Deng, Founder and Chief Executive Officer of XTransfer. </p>
<p>It is noted that Malaysia is also central to XTransfer&#8217;s regional strategy, with a plan to establish Malaysia as its regional operational hub, serving as a strategic control center within Southeast Asia, coordinating compliance, risk management, customer support, and global operations to ensure alignment with both local and group-wide standards. </p>
<p>&#8220;Malaysia gives us the talent, governance environment, and regional proximity to scale across the region,&#8221; Bill added.</p>
<p>Founded in 2017, XTransfer is dedicated to using technology to bridge large financial institutions and SMEs worldwide, providing secure, compliant, fast, convenient and low-cost cross-border trade payment and fund collection solutions. </p>
<p>The firm currently has more than 800,000 enterprise clients.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="MsYoJ0ZbQ4"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/11/19/xtransfer-partners-scb-to-boost-cross-border-payments/">XTransfer partners SCB to boost cross-border payments</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;XTransfer partners SCB to boost cross-border payments&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/11/19/xtransfer-partners-scb-to-boost-cross-border-payments/embed/#?secret=kpLSELgyaC#?secret=MsYoJ0ZbQ4" data-secret="MsYoJ0ZbQ4" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teleport’s revenue up 10 percent on year in the fourth quarter of 2025</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/teleports-revenue-up-10-percent-on-year-in-the-fourth-quarter-of-2025/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:05:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Logistics]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Teleport]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117499</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Teleport, the logistics arm of Malaysia-based Capital A, said it revenue grew 10 percent year on year to MYR 367 million ($94.45 million) in the fourth quarter of 2025 despite a 4 percent decline in Asia-Pacific market yield.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/A321F_1-348x348.jpg 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.teleport.it/">Teleport</a>, the logistics arm of Malaysia-based Capital A, said it revenue grew 10 percent year on year to MYR 367 million ($94.45 million) in the fourth quarter of 2025 despite a 4 percent decline in Asia-Pacific market yield.</p>
<p>The firm said in statement on Thursday that the company moved its highest volume of 102,688 tons (+19 percent year on year) and 63 million parcels (+165 percent year on year) with a new daily peak record of 974,000 parcels during the year. </p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s profitability momentum also continued in the fourth quarter of 2025, with Teleport recording a net operating profit (NOP) of MYR 5.2 million ($1.34 million), up MYR 7.5 million ($1.93 million) year on year. </p>
<p>For FY2025, Teleport achieved its highest-ever total volume of 347,885 tons (+18 percent year on year) and 167 million total parcels moved (+99 percent year on year), driving total revenue to MYR 1.2 billion (+11 percent year on year). </p>
<p>This growth validates Teleport’s unique asset-light model of combining passenger and freighter capacity of third-party airlines, AirAsia belly space and Teleport freighters to meet growing market demands for eCommerce. </p>
<p>Furthermore, this strong finish contributed to a full-year NOP of MYR 18.6 million ($4.79 million), a MYR 40 million ($10.29 million) turnaround from a MYR 21 million ($5.4 million) net loss in FY2024. </p>
<p>Teleport’s return to profitability at all levels was driven by strict cost and margin discipline, as well as a reduction in finance costs following the successful refinancing of the Deutsche Bank loan in the third quarter of 2025.</p>
<p>“Returning to profitability in 2025 is a testament to our team’s discipline, the trust our partners place in us and proves that Teleport’s asset-light model can scale profitably, </p>
<p>&#8220;Moving 167 million parcels and delivering MYR 1.2 billion ($310 million) in revenue proves that our model works at scale. This operating improvement, supported by the refinancing of our debt and a clear focus on both cost and margin discipline, gives us a solid foundation to scale further,&#8221; said Teleport Chief Executive Officer Pete Chareonwongsak.</p>
<p>&#8220;As we enter 2026, the $50 million in pre-IPO growth capital from HPS Investment Partners allows us to accelerate this momentum. While we remain mindful of shifting market yields and currency volatility, we are optimistic and clear about our goal of moving more global eCommerce with the same discipline that delivered positive earnings this year, </p>
<p>&#8220;By further integrating partner airline capacity with our own network, we are building a sustainable, global logistics infrastructure that has long-term earnings potential,&#8221; he added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="aVYXObuQXu"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/01/23/teleport-raises-50m-pre-ipo-capital-at-500m-valuation-to-scale-model-globally/">Teleport raises $50M pre-IPO capital at $500M valuation to scale model globally</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;Teleport raises $50M pre-IPO capital at $500M valuation to scale model globally&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/01/23/teleport-raises-50m-pre-ipo-capital-at-500m-valuation-to-scale-model-globally/embed/#?secret=mxHUwn0GQ0#?secret=aVYXObuQXu" data-secret="aVYXObuQXu" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GoTo clarifies path from startup to tech giant amidst public scrutiny</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/goto-clarifies-path-from-startup-to-tech-giant-amidst-public-scrutiny/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[GoTo]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117495</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />GoTo Group, Indonesia’s largest digital ecosystem, has released a comprehensive statement detailing its evolution from a 2010 call center to a public tech powerhouse. ]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2026/02/Screenshot-2026-02-27-155211-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://www.gotocompany.com/en">GoTo Group</a>, Indonesia’s largest digital ecosystem, has released a comprehensive statement detailing its evolution from a 2010 call center to a public tech powerhouse. </p>
<p>The firm said in a statement on Thursday that the move comes as the company seeks to provide clarity regarding its corporate governance, historical investments, and its relationship with founder Nadiem Makarim following recent legal proceedings.</p>
<p>A central point of the clarification involves GoTo’s relationship with Google. </p>
<p>While Google became a stakeholder in 2017, GoTo emphasized that the tech giant was never a majority or controlling shareholder.</p>
<p>According to the statement, all funding rounds were managed via standard Share Subscription Agreements (SSAs) with no &#8220;special treatment&#8221; for any specific investor.</p>
<p>GoTo also clarified that it never bought back its own shares from Google. </p>
<p>However, it did purchase Tokopedia shares from Google during the 2021 merger and restructured fintech entity shares (PT Dompet Karya Anak Bangsa) later that year.</p>
<p>In both instances, investors chose to reinvest the proceeds back into new GoTo shares.</p>
<p>Addressing the transition of founder Nadiem Makarim to public office in 2019, GoTo reiterated that Makarim resigned from all positions within the Group before becoming Indonesia’s Minister of Education, Culture, Research, and Technology.</p>
<p>To ensure a &#8220;clear separation of interests,&#8221; Makarim granted Power of Attorney (PoA) over his shareholder voting rights to his co-founders. </p>
<p>This effectively removed him from any decision-making role within the company for the duration of his public service.</p>
<p>GoTo also provided a deep dive into its internal financial shifts, specifically the relationship between PT Aplikasi Karya Anak Bangsa (PT AKAB) and PT Gojek Indonesia (PT GI).</p>
<p>As the company scaled, PT AKAB (a Foreign Investment Company) was established in 2015 to house the app’s technology. </p>
<p>To streamline for the 2021 initial public offering (IPO), PT AKAB took full control of PT GI.</p>
<p>According to GoTo, PT AKAB subscribed to newly issued shares in PT GI; PT GI used the proceeds (IDR 809 billion) to repay outstanding debts owed to PT AKAB. </p>
<p>The company also stated firmly that no individual shareholders, including Nadiem Makarim, received proceeds from these internal transfers.</p>
<p>In response to questions regarding share pricing, GoTo also explained the distinction between Nominal Value (required by Indonesian law) and the Subscription Price (determined by market demand).</p>
<p>GoTo also confirmed that these figures are clearly articulated in their financial statements, which are audited by independent firms and available for public review.</p>
<p>By detailing these milestones, GoTo aims to reinforce its foundation of trust and prudence. </p>
<p>The company said it remains focused on its mission to serve millions of consumers, drivers, and merchants across Indonesia, asserting that its &#8220;innovation is matched by transparency.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Xunbm7aHlR"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2026/02/10/goto-partners-mrt-jakarta-to-launch-tod-model-integrating-public-transportation-with-digital-platforms/">GoTo partners MRT Jakarta to launch TOD model integrating public transportation with digital platforms</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;GoTo partners MRT Jakarta to launch TOD model integrating public transportation with digital platforms&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2026/02/10/goto-partners-mrt-jakarta-to-launch-tod-model-integrating-public-transportation-with-digital-platforms/embed/#?secret=zwcCroVDPJ#?secret=Xunbm7aHlR" data-secret="Xunbm7aHlR" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singapore’s UltraGreen.ai delivers 24 percent revenue growth in FY2025 to $142.4M</title>
      <link>https://technode.global/2026/02/27/singapores-ultragreen-ai-delivers-24-percent-revenue-growth-in-fy2025-to-142-4m/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[TechNode Global Staff]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 07:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[HealthTech]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[UltraGreen.ai]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://technode.global/?p=117493</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />UltraGreen.ai Limited, the Singapore-based fluorescence-guided surgery and digital health solutions provider backed by Temasek entity 65 Equity Partners, has delivered 24 percent revenue growth in the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025) to $142.4 million.]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<img width="150" height="150" src="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" decoding="async" srcset="https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-150x150.png 150w, https://technode.global/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Screenshot-2025-12-03-171634-348x348.png 348w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><p><a href="https://ultragreen.ai/">UltraGreen.ai Limited</a>, the Singapore-based fluorescence-guided surgery and digital health solutions provider backed by Temasek entity 65 Equity Partners, has delivered 24 percent revenue growth in the financial year ended December 31, 2025 (FY2025) to $142.4 million.</p>
<p>The firm said in a statement on Wednesday that the results were driven by continued global adoption of Indocyanine Green (ICG) use in fluorescence-guided surgeries, across a growing range of procedures and specialties, alongside disciplined commercial execution as well as geographical expansion.</p>
<p>Its revenue growth was underpinned by both volume growth and improved pricing internationally. </p>
<p>Its sales volumes increased 13% year-on-year, while average selling prices rose across key markets, particularly in the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s gross margin maintained at 85 percent even as volumes continued to scale. </p>
<p>Its operating profit increased to $84.2 million, despite higher operating expenses associated with planned investments in commercial scale-up particularly in Asia, regulatory<br />
capabilities and initial public offering (IPO)-related costs.</p>
<p>The firm&#8217;s reported net profit after tax (NPAT) included net exceptional items of approximately $11.8 million. </p>
<p>Thiswas primarily related to a gain on the sale of discontinued non-core UltraLinQ business operations of approximately $23.7 million in August 2025, partially offset by a tax provision on dividend income of approximately $8.5 million and impairment and other charges totaling approximately US$3.4 million, including impairments related to assets held for sale and loss on disposal of intangible assets.</p>
<p>Excluding these exceptional items, the firm&#8217;s underlying NPAT increased 14 percent year-on-year to $63.8 million compared to $56 million.</p>
<p>The group ended FY2025 with no debt and a strong net cash position of $176.1 million, providing financial flexibility to support future growth initiatives.</p>
<p>“FY2025 marked a significant milestone for UltraGreen, culminating in our successful IPO in Singapore in December, with most of the offer being taken up by institutional investors, </p>
<p>&#8220;Even as we executed the listing process, we continued to deliver strong operating and financial performance and focus of our business model,&#8221; said Ravinder Sajwan, Chief Executive Officer and Executive Director of UltraGreen.ai.</p>
<p>&#8220;Looking ahead, we expect to continue delivering strong operational and financial growth, with FY2026 revenue forecast of between $170 million to $190 million,</p>
<p>&#8220;This outlook is driven by underlying business expansion, the full-year impact of pricing initiatives implemented in FY2025, and further penetration into new markets,&#8221; he added. </p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="drslwOi2u9"><p><a href="https://technode.global/2025/12/03/ultragreen-ai-receives-strong-demand-for-400m-sgx-ipo/">UltraGreen.ai receives strong demand for $400M SGX IPO</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted"  title="&#8220;UltraGreen.ai receives strong demand for $400M SGX IPO&#8221; &#8212; TNGlobal" src="https://technode.global/2025/12/03/ultragreen-ai-receives-strong-demand-for-400m-sgx-ipo/embed/#?secret=C8OQa6nrfx#?secret=drslwOi2u9" data-secret="drslwOi2u9" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
